<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">us-ppiu-camedi198201</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Edison Cylinder Collection, 1902-1916 <num>CAM.EDI.1982.01</num></titleproper><author>Melanie Root.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>ULS Archives &amp; Special Collections</publisher><p><date>July 2010</date></p><address><addressline>University of Pittsburgh Library System</addressline><addressline>Archives &amp; Special Collections</addressline><addressline>Website: library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 412-648-3232 (Thomas) | 412-648-8190 (Hillman)</addressline><addressline>Contact Us: www.library.pitt.edu/ask-archivist</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-07-08 17:27:39 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>ULS Archives &amp; Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Edison Cylinder Collection</unittitle>
    <unitid>CAM.EDI.1982.01</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/resources/802</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(84 Cylinders)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1916" type="inclusive">1902-1916</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e5e1a53b4ccde6383f31e5fc820bbd10" label="Abstract">The Edison Cylinder Collection represents both the songs and the sound recording technology of the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.  The songs range from Christmas tunes to Stephen Foster melodies and showcase American Popular Music through Thomas Edison's innovations.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9c351ff5c7b1e882f243e104adcda361">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The Center for American Music at the University of Pittsburgh assumes copyright for all materials in this collection.  Any reproduction or new work derived from the materials in this collection will have to be authorized by the University and the Center for American Music.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2b04b46f826b8e39b2661bf1644fb38e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection is largely unprocessed and unorganized.  A preservation survey has been conducted by Melanie Root in 2010 in order to determine which cylinders to keep in the collection, which can be salvaged and preserved, and which have to be deaccessioned.</p>  </processinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2a1e726330ee07b9386f8a930194da06">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Edison Cylinder Collection, 1902-1915, CAM.EDI.1982.1, Center for American Music, University of Pittsburgh</p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b85af0d0dcb9bf625777a33758472016">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>There are no content restrictions for this collection.  However, due to the nature of the material, the cylinders are to be handled in a very precise way.  They should not be held from the outside, but rather two fingers should be inserted into the core of the cylinder then separated to hold the cylinder in place while handling.  The oils and rubbing from touching the outside of the cylinder can do damage to the recording grooves in the wax or Amberol.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_fdeb46f23403cd3bb2d2fb9cdf225ae4">
    <head>Scope and Content Notes</head>
<p>This collection consists of 78 sound recording Edison cylinders.  The majority of the cylinders (55) are formatted on Blue Amberol cylinders.  Also included are black wax cylinders (13), grey wax cylinders (2), and a purple Amberol cylinder.  There are also six cylinders of unknown formats either due to their strange coloring and material, or to their fragility and thus were not able to be removed from their cases.</p><p>These cylinders showcase sound recordings from the first decades of the twentieth century.  Included are Christmas tunes, instrumental arrangements of popular parlor songs, dances, and a basic selection of Popular American music from between 1902-1916.  </p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6e295000f659e54c8093bccfa8dbe0fd">
    <head>History</head>
<p>By speaking the words "Mary had a little lamb," Thomas Edison successfully created the first cylinder sound recording in 1877 using tin foil as the recording medium.  A stylus created grooves in the medium that corresponded to sound.  This technique is not unlike modern vinyl records and LP's. However, Edison discovered that tin foil was not very durable and often only lasted through one or two playbacks. In the decade before the twentieth century, a switch to soft brown wax was made in the hopes that this material would outlast the tin foil as a recording medium for the spoken word as well as vocal and instrumental music.  </p><p>When the brown wax proved to be almost as problematic to maintain as the tin foil, Edison switched to black wax in 1902.  These black wax cylinders were slightly more durable then their brown wax relatives.  They also allowed for standardization of rotations per minute in playback speed making most of the Edison cylinders two minutes in recorded length.  </p><p>Soon after the wax cylinders became popular, another Edison innovation came about in the form of plastic cellulose.  This substance, most commonly referred to in the cylinders as Amberol, proved to be even more durable than the wax cylinders.  The most popular version used by Edison was the Blue Amberol cylinder.  This consists of a plastic cellulose cylinder with a plaster core.  These, along with the wax cylinders, were played on special rotating cylinder phonographs that were able to read the peaks and valleys with a needle, like a modern record player.   </p><p>With the emergence of the recorded disc, the Edison Cylinders fell out of vogue and were not made after the mid-1910s.  Today, the Library of Congress pays special attention to their brown wax cylinders because of the cylinders extreme fragility.  Of the surviving formats, these are most at risk of being lost forever.  The next most vulnerable are the black wax followed by the Amberol.  While both the black wax and Amberol are not as susceptible to mold and temperature fluctuation damage as the brown wax cylinders, they still require special care and housing to maintain their playability.</p><p>The Edison Cylinder Collection was gifted to the Center for American Music by its current director, Dr. Deane L. Root.  The cylinders were collected by Dr. Root's uncle who had an affinity for old sound recordings.  The Center for American Music accepted the gift due to the relevance of the recordings and their historic and research value to the University of Pittsburgh.  The cylinders are currently housed in the archive where light, temperature, and humidity can be monitored and controlled.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_6ad6293a4c9518f0b47e11f43b100eab">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection was left in its original order in the specialized case as well as on the top shelf of the audio case.  Because of this decision, there are no series or sections intellectually describing the cylinders in the finding aid.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="ulstag">Music</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cylinder recordings</subject>
    <genreform source="aat">Cylinders (Sound recordings)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Popular music -- United States -- 1911-1920</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Popular music -- United States -- 1901-1910</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Popular music -- United States -- To 1901</subject>
    <persname source="naf">Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva)</persname>
    <persname source="naf">Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864 -- Songs and music</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref8_676" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Dixie Medley" (Banjo)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171192</unitid><container id="aspace_3ef0e3cddc06c6c4cd10cfb8550ba2df" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0001</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_43ae965d5de9f359a2e7d4707c86ad79"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder.  The printed ID number on the rim reads 1532.  The performer is Van Eps.  The inside plaster core is chipped on the edges.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The case lid reads, "California and You (Harry Puck) performed by Billy Murray and Chorus." </p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by US Santa Barbara and can be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder634</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref10_8w4" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Carry Me Back to Old Virginny"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171193</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1916/1916" type="inclusive">1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_82518425bb5c270f24c72381b5ffd3dd" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0002</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b66f958ad58d4908279504c6ad124d72"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This item is a Black Wax Edison Cylinder recording.  The printed ID number on the rim of the cylinder is illegible.  There is a long thin scratch lengthwise across the cylinder.  It is not in its original case. The case lid reads "Down where the Swanee River Flows performed by George Wilton Ballard and Chorus."  A handwritten label is attached to the case which reads "Carry Me Back to Virginia."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_k2z" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Uncle Josh and the Insurance Company"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171194</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902" type="inclusive">1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_9bd4586ee358ceaf413474ff60eb0b43" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0003</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5807de9fa75d1b80c5b2c9e801d1820d"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison Cylinder recording.  The ID number printed on the cylinder is 913.  The performer is printed as Stewart.  There is a small crack in the wax about 1 centimeter long from the bottom lip of the cylinder.  It is not in a case.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_kbe" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Don't You Remember the Time"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171195</unitid><container id="aspace_1fd52b14c5b70d7ea91ff5d063095966" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0004</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_df35a580edb3ba5fe1ce9244cf02ea2d"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder recording.  The printed ID number is 4003.  The performer is printed as Louise Terrell and C. Ballard.  There is a small accretion stuck to the plastic cellulose.  It is in its original case, however, the lid is coming apart.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and can be streamed here: http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=4&amp;query=don%27t+you+remember+the+time&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;sortBy=&amp;sortOrder=id</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_epr" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Medley of Southern Plantation Songs"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171196</unitid><container id="aspace_ff24ce651848ae354e7206108bb875c9" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0005</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d7c5feb07241a5eaddfbc8f9bef7c4c1"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder recording.  Its ID number is printed as 1539.  The performer is printed as NY Military Band.  There is a small amount of discoloration on the bottom lip of the cylinder.  The inner plaster core is cracked and pitted on the edges.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The case lid reads "Climbing Up de Golden Stairs performed by Walter van Brunt and Chorus."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7251</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref19_4ve" level="item"><did><unittitle>"The Missouri Waltz"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171197</unitid><container id="aspace_042cea6f06671305f33fdc5c733b65ad" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0006</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92c208c9c0df111cb29a19aea7bf54e5"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder recording.  Its printed ID number is 2950.  The performer is printed as Jaudas' Society Orchestra.  There is some mold near the lip of the inner plaster core as well as some minor pitting ad cracking of the core.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The case lid reads "She Said 'Aloha' to Me Performed by Walter van Brunt and Chorus."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder492</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref21_bcd" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Peaches and Cream"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171198</unitid><container id="aspace_759ea076952f4f717065a7cd304c0fd9" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0007</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5aff256f4c6e99badf736c6a0369190e"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder recording.  Its printed ID number is 1971.  The performer is printed as Jones and L. Spencer.  There is some moderate mold on the plaster core as well as some pitting and cracking at the edges.  Several small cracks appear in the plastic cellulose at the bottom lip of the cylinder.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The case lid reads "Oh! How She Could Yacki Hacki Wicki Wacki Woo (That's Love in Honolulu) performed by Arthur Collins and Byron G. Harlan."  There is a handwritten label attached to the lid which reads "Peaches and Cream."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitzed by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder492</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref23_j45" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Let the Rest of the World Go By"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171199</unitid><container id="aspace_24cf72bbd5ac8bdf031845d3606e7b28" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0008</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7226cd62e2140004b660a586f3fd528a"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder recording.  Its printed ID number is 3955.  The performer is printed as Marion Cox and H. Hindermeyer.  The cylinder is in a case without a lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitzed by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder492</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref25_zyk" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Smiles"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171200</unitid><container id="aspace_1b19b2ea39f58da51c0ff42a7b97e2cc" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0009</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aebccd6523c03ba8f2f4a1ae973e594f"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder recording.  The printed ID number is 3613.  The performer is printed as The Harmony Four.  There is some mild mold damage to the inner rim of the plaster core.  The cylinder is in a case with no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7123</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref27_vv1" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Camp Songs US Army No. 2"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171201</unitid><container id="aspace_5871db1bb2277ca819bb77e828bb8f1d" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0010</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ce320decc14f97953f0900279d5193e5"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison Cylinder recording.  Its condition is unknown due to the inability to safely remove it from its case.  There is severe damage to the bottom of the case which may contribute to this situation.  </p><p>This cylinder has been digitzed by Syracuse University and may be heard here:
http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&amp;CISOPTR=686&amp;CISOBOX=1&amp;REC=13</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref29_a7f" level="item"><did><unittitle>"It's a Long, Long Way to Tipperary"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171202</unitid><container id="aspace_8d5a6107b2a60b3a698bb85c60c776ac" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0011</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7a2dea2d54f8e86df3ee628567777e1e"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Farrington and Choir, 2437.  There is some minor cracking of the plaster on the inner core at the bottom of the cylinder.  It is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitzed by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7167</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref31_d32" level="item"><did><unittitle>"A Perfect Day"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171203</unitid><container id="aspace_abe622e2a636dd1e8fee83c6e9db743f" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0012</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8dd0997b7900374cbab123717e3c91e"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Metropolitan Quartet, 2368.  The inner plaster core shows some slight mold damage and cracking at the top edge of the cylinder.  The cylinder is housed in the wrong case.  The case lid reads, "Vigoroso March, performed by the Newyork Military Band."  A hand written label is attached to the lid which reads, "Perfect Day."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7167</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref33_1i5" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Yaaka Hula Hickey Dula" (Hawaiian Love Song)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171204</unitid><container id="aspace_8decb300d5378944117ed0a3f519eeb4" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0013</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e683734ee3c41cf671aa48731e4d6c9"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as W. Van Brunt, 2915.  There is a fair amount of mold discoloration spread over the plastic cellulose.  The cylinder is housed in a case without a lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder879</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref35_ve5" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Dreamy Hawaii-Waltz"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171205</unitid><container id="aspace_fe995bac1ea93ebad4828cb147acaf71" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0014</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_727dcd28cfaef3bc3edb429b2454bec2"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Waikiki Hawaiian Orchestra, 4419.  There is some slight mold damage to the inner plaster core at the edges.  The cylinder is housed in a case with no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=21&amp;query=hawaii+songs+music&amp;num=1&amp;start=14&amp;sortBy=&amp;sortOrder=ia</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref37_tlx" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Don't Bite the Hand That's Feeding You"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171206</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902" type="inclusive">1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_5232c4a09ccac342eee2b7e4e6a20cae" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0015</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5e8fd4b142141a1edbf41568dd1fba79"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Campbell and Burr, 3378.  The inner core has severe mold damage.  The cylinder is housed in the wrong case.  The case lid reads, "When You're all Dressed up and No Place to Go - The Beauty Shop, performed by Billy Murray."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder8020</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref39_frt" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Napoli"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171207</unitid><container id="aspace_4cdfd2a255765edcd42409a8de2ba12c" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0016</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_084c547e3f0d5e5abf4e09898de2bdb1"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Imperial Marimba Band, 4180.  There is some slight mold damage to the bottom rim of the inner core.  The cylinder is housed in a case with no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitzed by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder1124</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref41_tje" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Waiting Down by the Mississippi Shore"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171208</unitid><container id="aspace_3718e89e03654cc1a29bf5d5fc6ad821" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0017</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b1bb83b646c73bcda153863d21ea58b6"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Campbell and Gillette, 1959.  There is some slight cracking of the inner plaster core near the edges.  The lid is in fragile condition but still legible.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder805</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref43_hwr" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Silver Bell"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171209</unitid><container id="aspace_d9ab399444c210eeb42bd0a3b00492f1" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0018</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5d896988dfc846712299f359802e17a"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The printed performer and ID number are Ada Jones and Murray, 1524.  There is some moderate mold damage and cracking of the plaster core at the edges.  The cylinder is housed in a case with no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder626</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref45_6ng" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Christmas Bells"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171210</unitid><container id="aspace_9dfad1256cdee3b41810bc58ace84ac9" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0019</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b24863e4b149e06b9581184679d30e36"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The printed performer and ID number are P. Gayler, 3870.  There is some slight mold damage and cracking to inner plaster core.  The printed lettering on the plastic is fading.  The cylinder is in its original case although the lid appears to have water damage and the label is beginning to fade.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;query=cylinder5985</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref47_z18" level="item"><did><unittitle>"My Waikiki Mermaid Hula Medley"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171211</unitid><container id="aspace_0687ef1261da8687d7dc2bc26a9e01f3" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0020</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_63c44839afda2c166677df038902926f"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The printed performer and ID number are Waikiki Hawaiian Orchestra, 3227.  There is some moderate mold damage and pitting of inner plaster core on the edges.  Something has been spilled and dried on the surface of the plastic.  This cylinder is housed in the wrong case.  The lid reads, "Something Seems Tingle-ingleing-High Jinks by Walter Van Bru[nt]."  There is also a smell of mold coming from the case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=4&amp;query=mermaid&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;sortBy=&amp;sortOrder=id</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref49_z0m" level="item"><did><unittitle>"You're a Million Miles From Nowhere"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171212</unitid><container id="aspace_7277099b0be759c1d3ae60f6623425d8" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0021</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b82dcdbdb5b4b48925bd71c709c8018b"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as W. Bonner, 3982.  There is some slight mold damage to the inner plaster core.  The plastic  has small vertical cracks in three places on the bottom rim.  The plastic has also faded to light blue on the bottom and top rims of the cylinder.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder6743</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref52_dkp" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Casey Jones"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171213</unitid><container id="aspace_441033616a9c9f5c9dc832df2e034a22" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0022</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_47053a9a5ee5278b9ab71502b166d37c"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as B. Murray and Choir, 1550.  A large portion of the inner plaster core has cracked away and is gone.  The cylinder is quite dirty and wrapped in paper instead of a case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder636</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref54_mbm" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Mother"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171214</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902" type="inclusive">1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_b163f4196d72fbf1dbd38fccb67e89c7" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0023</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d72a30b4eb836fe68b1e42c9ce0a0f9e"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type.  The performer and ID number are printed as Burr, 3351.  It is light blue in color.  Whether this is due to environmental wear or manufacturing is unknown.  The case does not have a lid.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref56_th3" level="item"><did><unittitle>"California and You"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171215</unitid><container id="aspace_06a03a999b882f271d8b72fba6a86e20" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0024</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8063dcd2a381e29061a751ab15061a81"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Murray and Choir, 2501.  There is some very slight pitting of inner plaster core at the edges.  The cylinder is housed in original case after transferring.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and my be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder903</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref58_d8m" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Mother Machree Violin"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171216</unitid><container id="aspace_4f33e7b07ff9c9876b0e5a9938f41323" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0025</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_02f1195a7c39360ed058a9bacdb93e9e"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Charles D'Almaine, 2419.  There is some slight pitting of the inner plaster core at the bottom edge.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder6551</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref60_ikb" level="item"><did><unittitle>"By the Light of the Silvery Moon"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171217</unitid><container id="aspace_67eb24ec557ff1b5753ecd1758125184" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0026</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a42eae562e2ea2c224650357f2d3b4ea"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID are printed as, Ada Jones and Chorus, 1521.  The cylinder is in its original case after transferring.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder0605</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref62_qns" level="item"><did><unittitle>"In the Town Where I was Born"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171218</unitid><container id="aspace_def602d92104e97102d0096b0854c7e5" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0027</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d1cde0aa25626d3cf6c7c9fd1db1b72"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, McCormack and Chorus, 2304.  There is some very slight mold damage in places on the plastic.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7247</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref64_3ik" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Yellow Dog Blues Fox Trot"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171219</unitid><container id="aspace_28cecfad749662f7b4fb3d93e812e7eb" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0028</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8b4ad9fa1bc6eeeeb80c17b1c8e3d924"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, H. Raderman's Jazz Orchestra, 3991.  There is some slight darkening of the plastic in places.  The case has no bottom or lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1016&amp;query=yellow+dog+blues&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;sortBy=&amp;sortOrder=id</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref66_oe5" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Sing of Love"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171220</unitid><container id="aspace_c10cc7cf25a99ff3767ca049f9b9a4ba" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0029</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e1d9f5cd0cfb607190b2dc1742b4a00f"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording. The performer and ID number are printed as, Venetian Instrumental Quartet, 2473.  There is some slight darkening of the plastic at the top edge of the cylinder.  The cylinder is in its original case after transferring.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref68_u6m" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Over There"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171221</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902" type="inclusive">1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_50c89d6f80e47902fde4ee441d768d63" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0030</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_262ecbc76e8dcc2be2569a5288b2e123"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type.  The performer and ID number are printed as Quartette, 3412.  The cylinder is light blue whether from environmental wear or manufacturing is unknown.  There is some slight rust on inner metal core.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The lid reads, "The Jolly Coppersmith."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here: 
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1016&amp;query=over+there+cohan&amp;num=1&amp;start=2&amp;sortBy=&amp;sortOrder=ia</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref70_nmm" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Rainbow"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171222</unitid><container id="aspace_8fc77bd6474a53242666aee6daa60e21" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0031</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b5f9780de9063e3310d5ad2bdbef2d66"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Ada Jones and Murray, 1884.  There is some darkening of the inner plaster core at the edges.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder193</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref72_21o" level="item"><did><unittitle>"How Could Washington be a Married Man"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171223</unitid><container id="aspace_e33f91408554b2ea42ba58f2112a172c" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0032</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72b1e254de8fe1c47dfbfe7674596038"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, M. J. O'Connell, 3086.  There is some very slight pitting around the top edges of the inner plaster core.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder5402</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref74_b0f" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Joan of Arc, They are Calling You"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171224</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902" type="inclusive">1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc81120275249e1dbf1f921897c7b3f7" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0033</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b06fba1317f796cbb139666feb934f9f"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Gillette, 3414.  This cylinder is light blue whether from environmental wears or manufacturing is unknown.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The lid reads, "The Missouri Waltz."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref76_emg" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Silver Threads Among the Gold"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171225</unitid><container id="aspace_813ec2a42ea9f1c69855271952b06586" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0034</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2363199ca7d9dd8314f3d86a7580316e"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Oakland, 1547.  There is some slight pitting of the inner plaster core on the top edge.  A large piece of the inner plaster core is missing from the bottom edge which has caused a slight malformation in the plastic.  The cylinder is in its original case.  The case lid appears to be water damaged.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder0615</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref78_4u8" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Dream of the Tyrolienne"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171226</unitid><container id="aspace_722f6b9ec40c481cada8bf49bf723d63" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0035</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0102d99852db592c675967a1f91b5c1e"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Venetian Instrumental Orchestra, 1795.  The cylinder was not able to be removed from the case for inspection.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The case lid reads, "I'm on My Way to Dublin."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder766</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref80_sqd" level="item"><did><unittitle>"You'd be Surprised"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171227</unitid><container id="aspace_d6db4740d19680f179000cb826b93429" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0036</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4e69210a6ca2bc2b4b6d317d65e82773"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, B. Murray, 3964.  There is some slight pitting of inner plaster core at the bottom edge.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and maybe be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7130</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref82_s5t" level="item"><did><unittitle>"I Laughed at the Wrong Time"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171228</unitid><container id="aspace_e219bfbe7c24b14d3bde3960299bc2e8" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0037</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_47d0a50672b4714d52d81f06d73aaefd"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Cal Stewart, 1852.  There are some slight cracks to the plastic on the bottom edge of the cylinder.  The plastic has also lightened and yellowed on the top one third of the cylinder.  Paper is stuffed into the cylinder in the top.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;query=cylinder4974</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref84_u5c" level="item"><did><unittitle>"I'm Looking for a Sweetheart"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171229</unitid><container id="aspace_4ca5e1e9f6455431f872dbc96c0a7f59" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0038</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ca094419ba135be51f9fb2b7e013cd33"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer is printed as Jones, Murray and Chorus.  There is no legible ID number.  There is some slight pitting of the inner plaster core on the edges.  There is also some slight yellowing of the inner plaster core in places.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7101</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref86_ynl" level="item"><did><unittitle>"The Tales of Hoffmann-Barcarole"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171230</unitid><container id="aspace_cade55f2f0bb4e071634b2074cca6aac" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0039</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dd79ada05370e7f64a1762b434c2a198"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, American Symphony Orchestra, 3070.  There is some very slight pitting of the inner plaster core at the top edge.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7602</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref88_vo6" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Kentucky Home"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171231</unitid><container id="aspace_a84a87c465f6c4b78279ebbeb0bc3930" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0040</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f2c7f7a049f73092445b53d5c288ef04"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Crescent Trio, 4420.  There is some slight mold damage to the inner plaster core at the bottom edge.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The lid reads, "Nearer My God to Thee."  The lid is in two pieces.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder8087</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref90_ivn" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Tell Mother I'll be There"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171232</unitid><container id="aspace_af38f68c553417c13a29a72de56e6112" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0041</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc93bee45b2ab107e6e28a665fd7e936"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Wheeler and Mixed Quartet, 1533.  There is some slight mold damage to the inner plaster core and plastic at the bottom edge.  The cylinder is in its original case and includes a leaflet about the song.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder609</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref92_7wx" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Swanee"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171233</unitid><container id="aspace_d530a9e2a510f632a7a4aec5ed558e08" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0042</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f7e7ba6e11aa8d54c51fe83e55a1d5a6"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Al Bernard and Frank M. Kamplain, 3988.  The cylinder was not able to be removed from the case.  The lid could not be safely removed and so the cylinder could not be inspected.  It is unknown if the cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7771</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref94_9yq" level="item"><did><unittitle>"We're Tenting Tonight"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171234</unitid><container id="aspace_e53f220757ae896fbfacf99b8d3f219b" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0043</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2bd587f0a9368de2e8e68290f5060279"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Knickerbocker Quartet, 1881.  There is some slight mold damage to the plastic on the bottom edge in places.  The case has no lid and is falling apart.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder0296</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref96_c2p" level="item"><did><unittitle>"I'm Sorry I Made You Cry"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171235</unitid><container id="aspace_d6d6272911e9eba0e04e8104c0ccfcaa" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0044</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b0497df23169d1189c8e5886eee85df2"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, H. Soman, 3655.  The inner plaster core is severely dirty.  The case has no lid and no bottom.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:</p><p>http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=4&amp;query=i%27m+sorry+I+made+you+cry&amp;num=1&amp;start=2&amp;sortBy=&amp;sortOrder=ia</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref98_elp" level="item"><did><unittitle>"I Might be Your Once-in-a-While Angel Face"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171236</unitid><container id="aspace_f949233eb466824645307769f2ff00f1" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0045</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_278afd6d2d72acc4df2ca2edbb47afa9"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Leola Lucy and Chorus, 4013.  There is some slight pitting to the inner plaster core.  There are also some spots or accretions on the plastic in places.  The cylinder has no case, only a lid with the correct title on the label.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder6526</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref100_x6y" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Coon Song, Abraham Jefferson Washington Lee"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171237</unitid><container id="aspace_94c2e80eacd6e01050008b342d02357a" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0046</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7968a4eecc1634254744dadc8e630b0f"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The ID number is printed as 9423.  There is no performer printed on the cylinder.  There is severe pitting and loss to the wax playing surface on a large portion of the cylinder.  The inner core is severely dirty.  The cylinder is unplayable.  It is in a case with no lid.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref102_2e8" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Nearer My God to Thee"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171238</unitid><container id="aspace_2c3c698e8e80941bc5b0146d864390ea" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0047</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f1a34e6527bc9f280df891dbf2c51825"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as Knickerbocker Quartet, 1557.  There is some very slight browning of the plastic on the top rim.  The cylinder is in the wrong case. The case has no lid.  The cylinder could not be transferred to the correct case as that case cannot be safely removed from another cylinder. </p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder641</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref104_dkk" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Somebody Cares"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171239</unitid><container id="aspace_c86f37a973cedd091c9088ffe94d8010" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0048</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e5118cc9b410f5400629b795094a53e5"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are listed as, Rodeheaver, 2354.  There is some very slight pitting to the bottom edge of the inner plaster core.  There are also some slight cracks to the bottom edge of the plastic.  The plastic is also lightening around the edges.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder155</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref106_m2a" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Annie, My Own-Fox Trot"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171240</unitid><container id="aspace_72dbf6b908787a94d54726d847c137dc" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0049</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c23ad7938ef6864ef117271955ade315"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, H. Radermann's Jazz Orch., 4217.  There is some very slight pitting to the inner plaster core.  There are also some moderate dirt accretions to the plastic in places.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=4&amp;query=annie+my+own&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;sortBy=&amp;sortOrder=id</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref108_oho" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Come Where My Love Lies Dreaming"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171241</unitid><container id="aspace_302870a9ee50bf8d08c13d02a7fa264f" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0050</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67281eeb08087e7cacfdca489f3c70a0"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Knickerbocker Quartet, 1933.  There are some slight cracks and yellowing to the top rim of the plastic.  The entire cylinder is lighter blue than normal for unknown reasons.  The case has a lid with no label.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder8706</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref110_5w1" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Old Black Joe"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171242</unitid><container id="aspace_5d54eec6f4d510b76ebaa50ca3ababc2" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0051</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_585a65139399160ee15299f96ad06811"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Knickerbocker Quartet, 1865.  There is some slight discoloration and mold damage to the cylinder.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder0190</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref112_csc" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Kentucky Home"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171243</unitid><container id="aspace_90990a29bbc86402860c6a51747cff82" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0052</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5df4c1a41eb269666a9e5df1051c979"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Crescent Trio, 4420.  There are some very slight mold accretion spots to the cylinder.  The case has a lid with no label.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder8087</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref114_wrc" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Unknown"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171244</unitid><container id="aspace_dbb908a7b8da5c36ef74aa51a5f7f7fe" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0053</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_07b5cd02dad3680c9153d5581a6560d7"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The ID number is printed as 8781.  The cylinder has crumbled into many small pieces inside of the case.  The performer and title of the cylinder could not be found on the pieces.  The cylinder is unplayable.  The case lid reads, "Old Folks at Home."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref116_mb4" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Hard Times Come again No More"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171245</unitid><container id="aspace_9656695f2c5a3b60bcd51a0196bd5aad" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0054</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ceead15b263d2213a1b890cf9404ad9b"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Quartette, 9120.  There is some very slight mold accretion and one pit mark on the wax.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The lid reads, "Bullfinches, Clarinet."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder2874</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref118_k99" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Old Folks at Home With Variations" (Piano)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171246</unitid><container id="aspace_79020ba2e6200c726c35de6df4f87307" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0055</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3166e845826f38dbdf3c111361e906bd"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Benoist, 1908.  There are some very slight cracks to the inner plaster core at the bottom of the cylinder.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and maybe downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder811</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref120_n2m" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Swanee"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171247</unitid><container id="aspace_cbcd2320fae51cf55bf61b02eadc98b5" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0056</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_afe849316b39a8a267d44742f3075911"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Al Bernard &amp; I Kamplain, 3988.  There is some slight mold damage and moderate pitting to the inner plaster core.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The lid is mostly illegible except for the ID number which reads, "3375."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7771</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref122_t85" level="item"><did><unittitle>"I Love the Land of Old Black Joe"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171248</unitid><container id="aspace_878dcccee21b52accd53fc4306b348bd" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0057</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_97133d619d115f1a716c863b523ad609"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Vaughn de Leath, 4097.  There are some rub marks on the plastic.  The case has an unmarked lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;query=cylinder1168</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref124_g5j" level="item"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171249</unitid><container id="aspace_74a810a1501ccf89c65d2dc66c2a7d25" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0058</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_56250c52301b07837904ef372efbb550"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type.  The cylinder has split into two pieces inside the case and cannot be safely removed from the case.  The case has no lid or bottom.  No writing is printed on the rims of the cylinder so the title, performer and ID number are unknown.  The cylinder is unplayable.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref126_6a1" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Swanee-One Step"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171250</unitid><container id="aspace_4669ecafc667b7a90042916e2304e807" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0059</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49e4092b8a76ae9f3cdd7fe0a8152b3d"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Lenzberg's Riverside Orch., 4034.  There are some rubbing marks on the plastic.  The case has a lid with no label.  The lid is in two pieces.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be streamed here:
http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&amp;CISOPTR=511&amp;CISOBOX=1&amp;REC=1</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref128_sqj" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Camp Songs, US Army - No.2"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171251</unitid><container id="aspace_0f6e5424fe68348dabbd921a8ba07fe1" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0060</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_50420d34ec0b5508ffa90c21f23043f4"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is an Edison cylinder sound recording case.  No cylinder was found in the case.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Chorus of Male Voices, 3403.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be streamed here:
http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&amp;CISOPTR=686&amp;CISOBOX=1&amp;REC=13</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref130_97e" level="item"><did><unittitle>"I've Got the Blues for My Kentucky Home"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171252</unitid><container id="aspace_bc74d5851c822256b43c67c348ebeaec" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0061</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b6f88c6919a2e5183d0996e34d8111af"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Premier Quar., 4219.  There are some rubbing marks on the plastic.  The case lid is illegible.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder1233</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref132_u9c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171253</unitid><container id="aspace_4c11198c8b32c7ddbbdc2062d59fd0fe" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0062</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_97fd94915fb71bcee0750c70e78a97c3"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The cylinder has crumbled into pieces inside of the case.  The performer, title, and ID number are not visible on any of the pieces.  The case has no lid.  The cylinder is unplayable.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref134_asn" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Prophete" - Ah! Mon Fils.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171254</unitid><container id="aspace_6309e7aef27340aef3b206b80c339c37" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0063</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72cdd847cfc1f53acecff7e4fce11945"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Marie Delna, 28126.  Some of the top of the inner plaster core has chipped away.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and can be downloaded or streamed here: 
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder1233</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref160_648" level="item"><did><unittitle>Song, "Old Folks at Home"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171255</unitid><container id="aspace_a18e49309b94f6a6145029423b634628" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0064</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_381766b32c0ca4e48d2fa0369536b1bf"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The Id number is printed as 8781.  There is no visible performer printed on the wax.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7224</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref136_0xk" level="item"><did><unittitle>Band, "Uncle Sammy March"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171256</unitid><container id="aspace_ef0c8a4321f44159eea9c0c13f35f24c" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0065</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b45c265f34b036ddacdef58405acaa54"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The ID number is printed as 8632.  There is no visible performer printed on the cylinder.  There is a long vertical crack through the wax as well as a small gouge near the middle of the cylinder.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder4355</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref138_x85" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Old Folks at Home With Variations" (Piano)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171257</unitid><container id="aspace_92909ffbf3557edd57070976343a62c1" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0066</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_71bc0ac4eb333dafd6e5eb4b62756a90"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Benoist, 1908.  There is some moderate mold damage and cracks to the inner plaster core on the bottom.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr%201=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder811</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref140_xbg" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Rock Me in My Swanee Cradle"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171258</unitid><container id="aspace_aff834cfa5ce5ca7846ad71c98f27053" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0067</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_686b49a4706d93335ec13d805aa13b40"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is an Edison cylinder sound recording of an unknown type.  The cylinder cannot be safely removed from the case for inspection.  The performer and ID number are printed as V. Dalhart and Chorus, 4605.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&amp;CISOPTR=991&amp;CISOBOX=1&amp;REC=7</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref142_ubn" level="item"><did><unittitle>"The Song of Songs"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171259</unitid><container id="aspace_3adedec24e6aac31aaff56fbf18352f0" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0068</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4cd16d04a48fec94c8c0f646a14c7bd2"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Leola Lucey, 4670.  The cylinder is dirty.  The case has a lid with no label.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by Syracuse University and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://digilib.syr.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/cylinder&amp;CISOPTR=681&amp;CISOBOX=1&amp;REC=9</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref144_6qc" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Old Dog Tray"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171260</unitid><container id="aspace_25849fc074cf4f784ba496af10375fba" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0069</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6ffb3bdceef5578647d16c7696521267"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, W. Van Brunt and Chorus, 3486.  There is some lightening of the plastic around the bottom lip.  The cylinder is dirty.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder5695</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref146_tk6" level="item"><did><unittitle>"I'm Forever Blowing Bubbles"- Medley Waltz</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171261</unitid><container id="aspace_a40357fefec5ae2ad43e829f815cdc05" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0070</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_881d33d4c993c1b4b90483da751f9b40"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Tuxedo Dance Orch., 3841.  There is some lightening of the plastic at the bottom lip.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder5962</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref148_bpn" level="item"><did><unittitle>Band, "My Old Kentucky Home"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171262</unitid><container id="aspace_a7f559ed4853b035e0f32ac644e028f1" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0071</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9d1738d635056074bc1391953435de88"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and most of the ID number are illegible.  There is severe mold damage and discoloration to a large portion of the wax surface.  There is also a large vertical crack through the wax as well as a piece missing from the top of the cylinder.  The cylinder is in the wrong case.  The lid reads, "What's the [?]i[?]se."</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder1615</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref150_q42" level="item"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171263</unitid><container id="aspace_770a7a7ab256e9655803be7ed80ddeab" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0072</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_729fa49f3806cdaa698f40122795604c"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Grey Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are not visibly printed on the wax.  Mold damage covers almost the entire surface of the cylinder.  Tape has been applied to the bottom of the case to act as support for the cylinder inside.  There is no lid.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref152_3g1" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Come Where My Love Lies Dreaming"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171264</unitid><container id="aspace_d90bfa821f5c6bac7c8a74c6a26139b0" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0073</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_74b57a0a7cb3477300681a584c925f18"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Purple Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Anna Case &amp; Criterion Quartet, 29022.  There are some small scratches and rub marks to the plastic.  The case has no lid.  The cylinder is in its original case.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref154_00w" level="item"><did><unittitle>Unknown</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171265</unitid><container id="aspace_7e1ac01d3743a152ca1de9ab674cf296" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0074</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f07f99f9be9a9ffe6e65e471293d864"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Grey Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer, title, and ID number are not visibly printed on the wax.  The surface of the wax is completely obscured by mold damage.  The case has no lid or bottom. Tape has been placed on the bottom of the case to support the cylinder inside.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref156_9wb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tenor, "For Sale, a Baby"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171266</unitid><container id="aspace_523ccf5419ab4d84267bac3de7418087" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0075</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2347ff0fc33ca6aaefa47e67608e16a"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The ID number is printed as, 8626.  There is no visible performer printed on the wax.  There is some moderate mold damage.  The cylinder is severely dirty.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder2725</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref158_qmy" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Come Where My Love Lies Dreaming"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171267</unitid><container id="aspace_97b710d1b4c19d6dc22c2519cfd39e5f" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0076</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2ab393eb48da771855c505df9eab1ac8"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Quartette, 9994.  There is paper stuffed inside of the cylinder.  The case, lid, and cylinder are all in excellent condition.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder3412</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref162_3wn" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Kentucky Dream"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171268</unitid><container id="aspace_ecd68b960fb956cdbef0471e39a714a9" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0077</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77fefdb4ce57125364fe89d2afdc6790"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Blue Amberol Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Leola Lucey and C. Hart, 3804.  There is some lightening at the top edge of the plastic.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder6993</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref164_zr6" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Mandy and Her Man"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171269</unitid><container id="aspace_2047fe3a7c489c41f4a61a0ea8d23cf5" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0078</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d053d4ea3ec1d3c3344083492e890925"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This is a Black Wax Edison cylinder sound recording.  The performer and ID number are printed as, Ada Jones and Len Spencer, 9236.  The cylinder is severely dirty with scratch and rub marks on the wax surface.  The case has no lid.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder8002</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref167_oxo" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Washington's Farewell Address"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171270</unitid><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_2d5413ccc6603e9c8297a5509d7af396" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0079</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c03f4adc7b85c9cd9cf731d123d3d4f8"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Cylinder is an Edison Blue Amber Record, marked 1654. Performed by Harry E. Humphrey.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;query=cylinder0715</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref170_gzs" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Battle Hymn of the Republic"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171271</unitid><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_6f595b622d7b59804f0508b03c230187" label="Audio" type="cylinder">Edi 0080</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9bb682ad6f9b996bb195a42a61cbd941"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Cylinder is an Edison Amberol four minute record, labeled number 79. The recording is performed by Miss Stevenson, Mr. Stanley and Chorus.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder7867</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref172_1t7" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Beautiful Ohio"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171272</unitid><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_95982561194732920c4eaf1e2815e9bb" label="Audio" type="cylinder">Edi 0081</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f968286b781e720c745bc336146afdc5"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Cylinder is an Edison Special four minute Amberol Record. The case is for "Tramp! Tramp! Tramp!" but the cylinder is actually for the Metropolitan Quartet's performance of "Beautiful Ohio," numbered 3759.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be downloaded or streamed here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder5909</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref174_ibr" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Coast Guard's March"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171273</unitid><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_fee68e7eb1c5705d5739b4a34a1875ee" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0082</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aea63e3cf516ee943bc98835eb6e79da"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Cylinder is in an unlabeled case for Gold Moulded Records. Cylinder is marked number 830.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref176_6vw" level="item"><did><unittitle>"The Rosary"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171274</unitid><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_27fcec8bcff7213f7c9b1f38c51c182d" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0083</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8eab30c926b30d1304b9dc50eaebb316"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Cylinder is an Edison Blue Amberol record labeled 1525. The recording is by Elizabeth Spencer and the Knickerbocker Quarter.</p><p>This cylinder has been digitized by UC Santa Barbara and may be streamed or downloaded here:
http://cylinders.library.ucsb.edu/search.php?queryType=@attr+1=1020&amp;num=1&amp;start=1&amp;query=cylinder628</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref178_ilc" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Schubert's Serenade"</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/171275</unitid><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial><container id="aspace_df15a9a568bee62dd4b5ee742ab2e135" label="Audio" type="cylinder">EDI 0084</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e0c575481bd726ad95dcb5a2a9f353c0"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Cylinder is a Columbia Phonograph Co. Grand Record, Number 4188</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
