<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead audience="internal" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="on_hold" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">us-ppiu-ais197706</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the John P. Robin Papers, 1943-2000 <num>AIS.1977.06</num></titleproper><author>Jason Bruegger and Troy Eisenhauer 2012-14.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>ULS Archives &amp; Special Collections</publisher><p><date>November, 2012</date></p><address><addressline>University of Pittsburgh Library System</addressline><addressline>Archives &amp; Special Collections</addressline><addressline>Website: library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections</addressline><addressline>Contact Us: www.library.pitt.edu/ask-archivist</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-06-11 09:53:07 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>ULS Archives &amp; Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John P. Robin Papers</unittitle>
    <unitid>AIS.1977.06</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">87 boxes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(87 boxes)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/2000" type="inclusive">1943-2000</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1994" type="bulk">1963-1994</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_35aa5997e92461c5432e51095efd37c7">add</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8ded669ff55846618130bcb0e478632e">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>No restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6efafca7f89cacd96aa3bfa3af8430d2">
    <head>Biography/History</head>
<p>John P. Robin, son of Peter and Bessie Robin, was born in Passavant Hospital in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, on October 15, 1912.  Robin spent his infancy in the coal mining town of McDonald, Washington County, Pennsylvania, located approximately 20 miles southwest of downtown Pittsburgh.  When Robin was three years old his parents moved the family to Pittsburgh and opened a pharmacy at Melwood Street and Centre Avenue in Oakland.  </p><p>As a student, Robin attended Pittsburgh public schools, eventually graduating from Schenley high school before enrolling to the University of Pittsburgh where he majored in biology.  Because of the Great Depression, Robin left school during his senior year prior to graduating.  In 1934, Robin secured a job with the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette as a writer; however, his time at the Post-Gazette ended in 1936 when Robin entered into local politics.  
In November, 1936, Robin went to work as the secretary for Pittsburgh Mayor Cornelius D. Scully.  Robin held that position until 1941 when the Mayor Scully appointed him Director of Welfare Activities in the city's Department of Welfare.  Robin temporarily left his political career during World War II when he enlisted in the Army, serving from 1943-1945.  Upon release from the Army, Robin returned to his hometown of Pittsburgh where in 1946 he was offered the position of Executive Secretary to Mayor David L. Lawrence.  That same year the Urban Redevelopment Authority (URA) was formed and Robin selected as its first director.  Robin would remain Executive Secretary and close confidant to Mayor Lawrence, as well as, serving at the director of the URA.  As director, Robin oversaw the development of projects, such as Gateway Center and Point State Park, during Renaissance I.      
During a nine month stretch in 1955, Robin left Pittsburgh for Harrisburg to join Governor George M. Leader's cabinet as Secretary of Commerce.  Robin returned to Pittsburgh in 1957 as president of the Regional Industrial Development Corporation (RIDC).  Later that same year, Robin moved to Philadelphia where he served as the Executive Vice President of the Old Philadelphia Development Corporation.  While there, Robin oversaw the redevelopment of Society Hill and Independence Mall.  
In 1963, Robin went to work for the Ford Foundation which relocated him to Calcutta, India.  In Calcutta, Robin served as the chief consultant to the Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Organization.  In 1967, Robin transferred to Nairobi, Kenya, where he spent three years directing Ford Foundation programs in nine East African Countries.  From Nairobi, Robin went on to Athens, Greece, where he worked on a worldwide study of the free world's developing urban centers.  
In 1973, Robin returned to Pittsburgh as a Professor at the University of Pittsburgh and an advisor to the Allegheny Conference on Community Development.  He served as the chairman of the URA board from 1977 to 1994 during Renaissance II while also serving as chairman of the Port Authority.  Robin also served as the chairman of the Port Authority Special Task Force, vice chairman of the Allegheny County Planning Commission, county representative of the Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission, the Mayor's Oakland Task Force, and the Mayor's Development Council.  John P. Robin died on May 07, 2000, at age 87.             
  </p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="aspace_e85f2cdeb3d31d95d251ccf3fdf5ab89">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The University of Pittsburgh holds the property rights to the material in this collection, but the copyright may still be held by the original creator/author. Researchers are therefore advised to follow the regulations set forth in the U.S. Copyright Code when publishing, quoting, or reproducing material from this collection without the consent of the creator/author or that go beyond what is allowed by fair use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7319c1d592e117a18aaffc2757f8550c">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was processed by Jason Bruegger and Troy Eisenhauer in 2012-14.</p>  </processinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_0641f49c3e8c98cf3e2d0b5e80719b84">
    <head>Previous Citation</head>
<p>John P. Robin Papers, 1943-2000, AIS.1977.06, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_6037ce02cc0d844da10d9a0f247445dd">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>John P. Robin Papers, 1943-2000, AIS.1977.06, Archives &amp; Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System</p>  </prefercite>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref7_104" level="series"><did><unittitle>The Academy for Contemporary Problems</unittitle><unitid>I.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/2000" type="inclusive">1972-2000</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2f0c651b7cc5f0f76048186135b7398"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains documents pertaining to the economics and future of American cities, and specific regions within the United States.  In addition, there is Academy for Contemporary Problems news releases, meeting minutes and agendas, newspaper articles, and professional correspondence documents.  There are also documents that specifically pertain to conferences such as the Aspen, Regional Growth Problems in U.S., and the Ohio River-Great Lakes conferences.     This series contains documents primarily pertaining to Allegheny County covering topics such as road needs, the neighborhood preservation program, education and teachers, and the Glassport, Bridgeville, Forest Hills, Crafton, and Verona redevelopment projects.  In addition, there are Allegheny County Planning Commission meeting minutes and agendas, budgets, multi-year plans/programs, newspaper articles, and professional correspondence documents.  There are also airport advisory committee reports, airport zoning committee minutes, and airport southern expressway documents.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref18_cg6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Report of the Panel on Title VII New Communities Program, The Future of the Industrial Midwest, Regional Institutes for Improving the Public Utilization of Technology, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Revitalizing Central City Investment, The Impact of Inflation of State and Local Government, Revitalizing the Northeastern Economy, Financial relief for trouble cities; Presentation folders containing – Policy Options for Neighborhood Empowerment, Multistate Institutions and Regional Growth Rural Development Issues, Newspaper articles; Loose documents pertaining to – Balanced Growth for the Northeast: Is it Possible?, News releases, Profession correspondence, Managing Urban Transition, The Demographic Future of the Cities of America</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/2000" type="inclusive">1972-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdd0405c0a6e3c6c4211b0c99eb7ca65" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref17_e1v" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Communities Legislation, Aspen Conference, Conference on Regional Growth Problem, Conference on Ohio River-Great Lakes, National Growth Policy; Bound reports regarding - Proposal for Designing an Economic Development Research Strategy for the Northeastern Region of the United States, Designing an Economic Development Strategy for the Great Lakes Region, The Academy for Contemporary Problems 1976 Annual Report, Financing of County Capital Improvements, A New Administration Mechanism for Allegheny County, The Pittsburgh Civic System: An Overview; Presentation folders containing – Future National Policies Concerning Urban Redevelopment; Loose documents pertaining to – Newspaper articles, Professional correspondence, various meeting agenda and minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1981" type="inclusive">1972-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_f45cde993d30d7286a25b66555e43b13" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">82</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref8_779" level="series"><did><unittitle>Allegheny County Planning Commission</unittitle><unitid>II.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1989" type="inclusive">1966-1989</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a34d2b957f87402c14ec6b7297596d05"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains documents primarily pertaining to Allegheny County covering topics such as road needs, the neighborhood preservation program, education and teachers, and the Glassport, Bridgeville, Forest Hills, Crafton, and Verona redevelopment projects.  In addition, there are Allegheny County Planning Commission meeting minutes and agendas, budgets, multi-year plans/programs, newspaper articles, and professional correspondence documents.  There are also airport advisory committee reports, airport zoning committee minutes, and airport southern expressway documents.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref19_ccs" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Allegheny County Road Needs Study, Capital Monitoring System Updated report, Subdivision Regulations, Allegheny County Neighborhood Preservation Program, Housing in Allegheny County; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the Board minutes, Professional Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1976" type="inclusive">1974-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea0a5c6964bff7f54c31d70f9b4292cb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref20_1vz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound report regarding – Capital Improvement Budget; Loose documents pertaining to – Profession correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1eabbb66c102cc3d2d0d356d225a98a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref21_qrr" level="file"><did><unittitle>Armstrong County Planning Commission Data Resource Manual, Aero-Notes, Allegheny County Planning Commission – Search committee, Airport Zoning Committee minutes, Community Development Act, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Development Sketch Plan for Armstrong County, Six Year Plan and 1978 Capital Budget, Rural Water Improvement Plan, Turtle Creek Watershed Erosion and Sedimentation Control Study; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, meeting minutes, progress reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1979" type="inclusive">1973-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b27c13b33626bb7415152bc5f2d090b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref22_2hy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Catalog of State Assistance to Allegheny County; bound reports regarding – 1978 Capital Budget Year End Summary report, Capital Improvements Budget (1975-1976), Capital Improvements Program, Capital improvements progress Report, Preapplication for Feasibility Study for an Energy/Resource Recovery Facility; Loose documents pertaining to  meeting agenda and minutes, Profession correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1981" type="inclusive">1975-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d980eb1e935f9333596a4a9660e12b9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref23_f7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Allegheny County Planning Commission – Meeting agenda and minutes; Bound reports regarding – 1981 Financial Report Summary, Six Year Capital Development Program, Marina Study, Planning Department Annual Report, Borough of Homestead Redevelopment Area Basic Condition Report, Proposed Redevelopment Area of Borough of Braddock; Loose documents pertaining to – meeting agenda ad minutes, Professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1989" type="inclusive">1981-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_946b4dcc0c34c6360597a5b71016aa5e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref24_v1g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Southwestern PA Regional Planning Commission; Bound reports regarding - Transportation Improvement Program for SPRPC Region, Pitcairn Rail Yards Redevelopment Area: Basic Conditions Report, The First Two Years: The Public Education Fund, Mini-Grants for Teachers, Partners in Education, Allegheny County Capital Budget Report, Allegheny Conference on Community Development Report, Port Authority of Allegheny County Annual Report; Loose documents pertaining to – various meeting agendas and minutes, Professional correspondence, newspaper articles, Progress reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1987" type="inclusive">1977-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_49938c8d16a03c522fa380893ad73adb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">33</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref25_ja7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Block Grant Program, Allegheny County Planning Commission meeting agenda and minutes, Professional Correspondence; Bound reports regarding - The Pennsylvania Energy Primer, Report on Existing Condition Proposed Glassport Redevelopment Area, Allegheny County Grantee Performance Report, Report on Existing Conditions Proposed Bridgeville Redevelopment Area, Proposed Forest Hills Redevelopment Project, Proposed Verona Redevelopment Project, Housing Programs in Allegheny County, Subdivision Regulations ; Loose documents pertaining to – Meeting agenda and minutes, Newspaper articles, Professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1982" type="inclusive">1979-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_0860a76b270f86ffa2e5105c062083b5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">47</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref26_ubz" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding - Planning for Allegheny County, Pacesetter Report, Report on Existing Conditions: Proposed Crafton Redevelopment Area, Allegheny County Grantee Performance Report, Allegheny County Comprehensive Community Energy Management Action Plan, Water and Wastewater Residue Management Study, Certification of Blight: Braddock Borough, Allegheny County Subdivision and Land Development Regulations, Certification of Blight: Dormont Borough, Final Report and Proposed Home Rule Charter, Allegheny County Proposed Land Use Plan, Verona Redevelopment Project; Loose documents pertaining to – various meeting agendas and minutes, Newspaper articles, Professional correspondence, Proposed projects, Energy Audit</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1986" type="inclusive">1966-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f5756e155e74334c4ed17a1437c2d6e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">85</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref9_6lj" level="series"><did><unittitle>Citizens Task Force on Refuse Disposal</unittitle><unitid>III.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1981" type="inclusive">1972-1981</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15af4e3e675da7315eb23a73286d4846"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains documents pertaining to solid waste and includes reports, articles, and resolutions on solid waste disposal.  In addition, there are Citizens Task Force on Refuse Disposal meeting minutes and agendas, newspaper articles, Allegheny County Sanitary Authority annual reports, and professional correspondence documents.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref27_fge" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various articles, reports, and resolutions; Professional correspondence, newspaper articles, Waste Age Magazine; Bound reports regarding – How Shall We Collect the Garbage?, Hidden Waste: Potential for Energy Conservation, Proposed Solid Waste Processing and Resource Recovery; Loose documents pertaining to – various documents and professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1981" type="inclusive">1972-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ac0232b02a9b40104cffb215ad62936" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">87</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref10_fn9" level="series"><did><unittitle>The Ford Foundation</unittitle><unitid>IV.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/2000" type="inclusive">1947-2000</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8483827fe0c6a266c3ccb08638e8d8b8"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains multiple volumes of the Ford Foundation Letter, annual reports, professional correspondence documents, newspaper articles, various versions of a comprehensive report Robin was involved in preparing concerning urban revitalization in foreign countries, and various papers authored by Robin.  In addition, there are documents pertaining to topics, such as urban redevelopment programs, in several countries including Nigeria, Kenya, Argentina, Venezuela, Columbia, Mexico, Pakistan, Peru, Chili, Brazil, Panama, Philippines, Tanzania, Malaysia, Singapore, Turkey, Thailand, Uganda, Zambia, Ghana, India, Calcutta, Bombay, and Lebanon.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref28_9dj" level="file"><did><unittitle>News releases, Ford Foundation Letters, Bound reports regarding – Four Foundation annual reports, A Decent Place to Live, About the Ford Foundation, Current Comment of the Ford Foundation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1973" type="inclusive">1963-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_6951fc6b291d2279433bce8e646dc9ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13-B</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref29_zq5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Final Report 1972 –draft and scrap notes; Professional correspondence, The Next Decade: Recommendations for the Ford Foundation-Vol. I:Part II, Various documents concerning Nigeria, Nairobi, and Kenya – Annual reports, maps, professional correspondence, newspaper and journal articles, and bound reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1973" type="inclusive">1966-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3297aad9c9d486eee3df8ee1e0175c3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref30_5bi" level="file"><did><unittitle>Professional correspondence, Ford working paper, Final report – first draft, working paper, Discussion papers I, II, and III; Papers and Memos brought back from Delhi, Bound reports regarding – International Urbanization Survey: Final Report, A Survey of Regional Planning Research Activities in Western Europe and Yugoslavia, The Next Decade: Recommendations for the Ford Foundation, Infrastructure Problems of the Cities of Developing Countries</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_b958643e971d069c093d8bbf18385776" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref31_mhk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Survey of North American Programs, Working draft and original final concerning Argentina; Various documents concerning – Teaching, Research, and Higher Education, and Educational Assistance for Developing Countries; Working draft concerning Venezuela; 1969 Annual Report, Proposed Structure of the Regional Centre for Urban problems and Planning, The Impact of The University of Pittsburgh on the Local Economy, Newsletter, Belgrade Rapid Transit Study Design Report, professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Spatial Policies for Regional Development, the Ford Foundation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1973" type="inclusive">1969-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa503a6f885d5ed1c98c01b55eefe3ae" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref32_k3m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning - Mexico, Columbia, Chile, Brazil, Peru, and Pakistan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/2000" type="inclusive">1966-2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb555745f2d95c52d805e6e277b49051" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref33_v7i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planning and Development Collaborative International – Information and Quarterly Newsletter; Various documents concerning - Pakistan, Institute of Business Administration: University of Dacca, and the Philippines</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1972" type="inclusive">1963-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_b230cf7464b91a6b7c8f81f864a8dfb6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">35</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref34_e88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Plans and Policies for Karachi, Physical Planning and housing Section of the National Planning Commission, Welfare Aspects of National Policy Toward City Sizes, Changing Relations Between Urban and Rural Areas in the Economic Development of Mexico, Fellowship Programs in Natural resources and Urban Economics; Papers authored by Mr. Robin – The Shaping f the Urban World, Robert Pease interview, Urban Research: Usage and Abuse, The Complicators and the Simplifiers: Do We Really Have an Urban Crisis; Bound reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1974" type="inclusive">1960-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_b73960ded81935dbaba1255bd8db2c8a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">36</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref35_cyd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Tanzania, Malaysia, Singapore, Dakar, Turkey, Thailand; Papers and Talks – Problems of a Growing Population, Education and Social Values, The Quality of Urban Life with Special Reference to Developing Countries; Bound Reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1972" type="inclusive">1967-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_6df686173b8884c926d047d1ccc10d93" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref36_4mx" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Uganda and East Pakistan, World Health Organization (W.H.O.), Centre for Housing &amp; Development U.N., Bound reports regarding – Uganda and Nigeria; Loose documents pertaining to – Inter-Regional Seminar on Improvements of Slums and Uncontrolled Settlements</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1973" type="inclusive">1966-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_9bd43f988cdaf90d865643262e221699" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref37_92g" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Uganda and Pakistan, U.N., UNESCO, UNICEF; Bound reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1972" type="inclusive">1957-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_dba1d20532feba7800b4976123f45ff9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">39</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref38_q9z" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous documents on U.S., New York, and Pennsylvania; Agriculture, U.S. Foreign Assistance, AID, HUD, Inter-Agency Consolidated report Latin America/Caribbean Region; Bound reports regarding – Latin America, Ghana, Ethiopia, Outdoor Recreation for America, Delaware River Basin report, Publically Provided and Assisted Housing in the U.S.A., The Nature, Impact, and Prosecution pf White Collar Crime; Loose documents pertaining to – Department of State, Agency for International Development reports, A Housing program for Latin America</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1976" type="inclusive">1960-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_b7dca81b3c87ee8603c3a94a68baf6ff" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref39_hfj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Zambia, Venezuela, Latin America, and Wayne State; Bound Reports regarding - Zambia, Belgrade, Malaysia; Presentation folder contain – The Food Crisis, Food: Means of Life, Newspaper articles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1975" type="inclusive">1965-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_cd40a2bd9ecbdd9a05ba56d53c2e875c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">41</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref40_sy1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Zambia; Bound reports regarding – Nigeria, Pakistan, WHO, The Coming Urban Crisis in Asia</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1975" type="inclusive">1969-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0d62de4a52bba62288e5c9d8412045a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref41_ric" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Brazil, Latin America, South East Asia, East Africa, Egypt; Plan of Operation for Urbanization Study, Papers on Planning, Professional Correspondence, Newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – India</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1972" type="inclusive">1960-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_24e92fda1fa97c8f5490d50ffe647c05" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">48</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref42_yv5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Ghana, Kenya, Tanzania, Nigeria, Zambia, Pakistan, Indonesia, Thailand, Columbia, Venezuela; Ford Complied documents, Urbanization Survey, Update to Travel and Study manual, Grant Proposals, Bound reports regarding – Management and Program Trends in the Fifties and Sixties, The Foundation and the Less Developed Countries the Decade of the Seventies, Overseas Development Self-Study of the India Program, Lima Field Office Annual Report</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1973" type="inclusive">1947-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_525769bed3bf0646a8cee6ea343ee1f9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">49</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref43_96a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Africa, India, South East Asia, Stockholm; Conference on Urbanization, Environment, Employment in Less Developed Countries; Bound reports regarding – The Foundation's Work on Population, reports in foreign languages,; Presentation folder containing – information on the Foundation for Cooperative housing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1972" type="inclusive">1956-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_98c5273723568c8e117eb92f134784b7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref44_en9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planning School Kumasi, Ghana: Team report, Bound reports regarding – Ghana, Jamaica, Peru, Chile, Race and the Third World, International Urbanization Survey Findings and Recommendations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_eea83027a703a9155c1deef45affa5e8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">51</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref45_lux" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – India, Kenya, Nairobi, Columbia, Venezuela, Latin America; Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Nairobi, Kenya, Draft Programme and Budget (1970-1971), Site and Service Schemes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1972" type="inclusive">1964-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_65572143a249bf7e787bd55c703a49b0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref46_02s" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – India, Indonesia; Papers on Inter-American Development Bank; Bound reports regarding – India, Tanzania, Latin America</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1989" type="inclusive">1958-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad06a0609006c36bc139112a4e804817" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">53</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref47_bun" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Lebanon, Beirut, Madagascar, Malaysia, Morocco, Mexico; Bound reports regarding – Mexico, Malaysia</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1972" type="inclusive">1966-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_69479ba20a8d26d65498f61772954b6d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref48_sx6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Nigeria, Latin America; National Academy of Science, The National Urban Coalition 1973 Budget, Papers and Conferences sponsored by O.A.S. on Urban Development; Bound reports regarding – Nigeria, Prospects of the World Food Supply</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1973" type="inclusive">1966-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_aeb74052f8e89a518daa613694f256cb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref49_srj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Terzo working papers, Talking Points: Rosser – draft reports and memos, working notes, professional correspondence, Various documents concerning – Calcutta; Bound reports regarding – South Africa, International Urbanization Survey: Findings and Recommendations, Ekistics magazine; Loose documents pertaining to – East Africa, The Political Implications of Demographic Change in Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, Urban Research: Usage and Abuse</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1989" type="inclusive">1969-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_a949e407ed0758f9d3a90ca19bd06782" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">61</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref11_7t3" level="series"><did><unittitle>Pittsburgh City Planning Commission</unittitle><unitid>V.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1997" type="inclusive">1971-1997</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b61bb0cd85458320f130c11d8f4b53e0"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains documents such as Planning Commission meeting minutes and agendas, budgets, multi-year plans/programs, and professional correspondence documents.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref54_cuq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pittsburgh City Planning Commission agendas and minutes; Bound reports regarding – Pittsburgh Budget 1979, Housing Authority Annual Report; Loose documents pertaining to – Pittsburgh City Planning Commission addenda and minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1981" type="inclusive">1977-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_c03eff4abdd62cd3f3be02608c707859" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">58</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref55_r9l" level="file"><did><unittitle>Allegheny County Planning Commission agenda and minutes, Pittsburgh City Planning Commission agenda and minutes; Bound reports regarding Draft Six Year Development Program and 1993 Capital Budget; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1993" type="inclusive">1989-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_b29761bbae21f628c3e5a0f232945f62" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">75</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref56_80m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pittsburgh City Planning Commission agendas and minutes, Allegheny County Planning Commission agenda, minutes, and Six Year Capital Development Programs; Bound reports regarding – Progress in the Neighborhoods: 1983-1988, City of Pittsburgh Six Year Development Programs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1997" type="inclusive">1983-1997</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5f5887ce29cd9105affd10118452bd6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">76</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref57_9h7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Loose documents pertaining to – Pittsburgh City Planning Commission agenda and minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1986" type="inclusive">1981-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_9cb08625b6e6fe005b807829f3d5dc4a" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">84</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref12_8nt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Port Authority of Allegheny County</unittitle><unitid>VI.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1993" type="inclusive">1970-1993</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ee7e16bbb48ea6a0e8db23f5dc9a2adb"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains Port Authority board packets for both regular meeting and special meeting which contain minutes and agendas.  There are staff reports to the board, newspaper articles, PA Transit News publications, professional correspondence documents, proposed operating budgets, monthly financial reports, Port Authority resolutions, Audit and Finance Committee meeting minutes, Consumer Relations Committee meeting minutes, PAT's People Flyer publications, letters from the public, strategic plans, and Planning and Construction Committee minutes and agendas.  In addition, there are documents pertaining to specific projects such as the East Busway Feasibility study, South Hills Alternative Analysis study, Commuter Rail, Mon Valley Transit study, Pittsburgh Light Rail, South Hills Light Rail, and airport busway.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref64_8u5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board membership, Port Authority newspaper articles, South Hills alternative analysis study, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Board meeting reports, Population estimates (1975), Proposed operating budget (1976); Loose documents pertaining to – Transit in Toronto, Mass Transit Canada</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1976" type="inclusive">1973-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_91241d1afd210f8c3f5e529b465f1503" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d9ea0edacb062a5c40a708c9c36baae9"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Box 1 includes: Board Membership, 1973-1974, P.R., 1973-1975, Newspaper Articles, PA Transit News Articles, South Hills Alternative Analysis Study, Professional Correspondence , Bound Reports (35), 1975-1976, Regular Meeting of the Board, Special Meeting of the Board, Staff Report to the Board, 1975 Population Estimates, East Busway Feasibility Study, Proposed Operating Budget, 1976, Transit in Toronto, and Mass Transit Canada</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref65_hgt" level="file"><did><unittitle>Transportation Task Force professional correspondence, Transportation Task Force Technical Committee meeting minutes, Transportation Task Force consultant applications professional correspondence,  South Hills Corridor transit alternative evaluation, Supplemental Memorandum on Early Action Program; Bound reports regarding – Reports on Workmen Compensation Dilemma, South Hills Corridor transit alternative evaluation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1976" type="inclusive">1973-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_9bd96496d5f140b59062c591d53e682b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d063a21fddc627e9ffaf1cedcfe3c752"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>Box 2 includes: Transportation Task Force, 1975-1976, Professional Correspondence, Technical Committee, 1975, Meeting Minutes, Consultant Applications 1975, South Hills Corridor Transit Alternatives Evaluation, Minutes 1973-1975, Supplemental Memorandum on Early Action Program, Bound Reports (9) 1974-1976, Report on Workmen's Compensation Dilemma, South Hills Corridor Alternatives Evaluation, Port Authority Regular Meeting of the Board, publications-1975-1976, and Meeting Minutes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref66_c82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Proposed operating budget, PAT Staff report to the board, PAT regular meeting to the board, Commuter rail potential, Audit report</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1976" type="inclusive">1973-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2bb754c0f3c2169afe3c4481c5d11d9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref67_m55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority regular meeting of the board, PAT Quarterly progress report, South Hills Corridor transit alternative evaluation, Port of Pittsburgh fact finder; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1978" type="inclusive">1976-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_9615d9abccfa232a2010b1e1f1afd05d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref68_k00" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newspaper articles, Transportation ask Force minutes; Bound reports regarding –Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Quarterly progress report, American Public Transit Association Journals; Loose documents pertaining to- Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1977" type="inclusive">1970-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef3d52067fc64fad4d05387dd75832b0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref69_zc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newspaper articles, Professional correspondence, Operating budget (1977); Bound report regarding – Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Quarterly progress report, Federal transit subsidies; Loose documents pertaining to - Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Mass Transit Magazine, Port Authority People Flyer, Port Authority News releases</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1977" type="inclusive">1974-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_149a5bfab04ff0268850d6c2932f1d75" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">9</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref70_olv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Professional correspondence, Port Authority resolutions, Agenda of the Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Testimony of Executive Director James R. Maloney, Transit advertising and the Port Authority, Financial statements; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Population estimates (1976), Bridge closing impact study; Presentation folders on – Light Rail, here Rivers Regatta, Toronto Transit Commission; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority News releases, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting f the board agenda, Transit in Toronto, Public Transportation, Transit Journal, Light Rail Today, The Future of Rail transit</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1980" type="inclusive">1975-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_8cb18772f7691d409822e5353b586677" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref71_yuj" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audit and Financial Committee professional correspondence, Audit and Financial Committee meeting minutes, Consumer Relations/Operation Committee professional correspondence, Pennsylvania Transit Financial Conference (1985), Budget professional correspondence, Port of Pittsburgh; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Operating budget (1986), Disadvantaged Business Enterprise Program, Chronology (1985), Mon Valley Transit study, Comprehensive Marketing Plan, Survey of State Involvement in Public Transportation (1984); Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Senate Bill No. 825, Newspaper articles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1987" type="inclusive">1982-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_91cab6bb6f3a99f12829cbba584a4de5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref72_7du" level="file"><did><unittitle>Consumer Relations Committee meeting minutes, consumer letters, Construction Committee meeting minutes, Audit and Finance Committee meeting minutes, Administration Committee meeting minutes; (1982) Port Authority Regular Meeting of the board - Meeting minutes, Meeting agenda, Professional correspondence; (1988) Port Authority Regular meeting of the board – Meeting minutes, Meeting agenda, Professional correspondence, Staff report to the board; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Proposed access fares, Recommendations, to improve the fare structure; Loose documents pertaining to – Meeting agenda, meeting minutes, Professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1988" type="inclusive">1980-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_219cc1e4ac23cf292f9bec42051f7409" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref73_dtm" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Strategic Plan (1987-1991), Pa Monthly financial report, Port Authority Strategic Business Plan (1986-1990), Port Authority Operating Budget (1986), Transit Fact Book; Loose documents pertaining to – Mayor's Development Council meeting minutes, Professional correspondence, Pa Inter office correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Rider comments and suggestions</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1991" type="inclusive">1981-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d5f1e4b2dd54146d8b09cfb8a05776d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref74_g3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1977" type="inclusive">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8d9bb00bc86ce2038ea4eb5522b9709" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">32-B</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref75_hle" level="file"><did><unittitle>Port Authority Regular meeting of the board –  agenda, professional correspondence, inter office correspondence; Newspaper articles, Employment Impacts, of Transit Capital Investment and Operating Expenditures, Monthly financial report, Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Mass Transit Magazine, Bus Ride Magazine, Public Hearing on Proposed Fare Increase and Service Reductions, Port Authority Staff report to the board; Presentation folder – Professional correspondence, Metro Magazine; Loose documents pertaining to –PA Transit news releases, Professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1983" type="inclusive">1979-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1e30db27e5ca52ac6ab8a2ed411f9d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">43</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref76_5ep" level="file"><did><unittitle>Port Authority Regular meeting of the board and Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence, Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Port Authority Fact Finder; Port Authority Inter office correspondence; Baumbash – Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Staff responses to opinion and order, Port Authority Transit Funding Study; Loose documents pertaining to – PA Transit news releases, Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Inter office correspondence, Newspaper articles, Port Authority People Flyer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1982" type="inclusive">1979-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_c88d5a7a5749dc3733f8354d74db67fd" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">44</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref77_aqo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Court case documents, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Port Authority Code of Performance, Professional correspondence, inter office correspondence, Request for Proposal: Streetcar System Derailment Evaluation, Port Authority Monthly financial report, Transit Advertising and the Port Authority; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, A Revised Transportation Plan of Southwestern Pennsylvania, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, The Highway Fact Book, Port Authority Hearing on Proposed Fare Increase and/or Service Reductions, Graphics Standard Manual; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Special meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence, Photocopy of a letter to James Maloney from President Carter, A Survey of Local Mechanisms for Finding Transit Operating Costs, Request for Proposal for the Operation of a County Wide Shelter Program, PA Transit news releases</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1981" type="inclusive">1977-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3c470ad848fb7ba0683323b6238222e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">45</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref78_5t7" level="file"><did><unittitle>John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, minutes, and agendas, Professional and Inter office correspondence, Port Authority Staff reports to the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Newspaper articles, "When the Courts Decide the Fares," A Report of the Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh; Renaissance II, Report on Transit Operations, Information on Street Cars, Affirmative Action Plan for the Minority Business Enterprise,; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes, Port Authority Monthly financial report, Operating budget (1979), Port of Pittsburgh Profile, PA Transit news releases, Audit report of Port Authority</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1982" type="inclusive">1973-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2c1a501b4552fd05922f1c996028c32" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref79_9lj" level="file"><did><unittitle>John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, and agendas, Port Authority Staff reports to the board, Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports, Professional and Inter office correspondence, The Academy for Contemporary Problems memorandum, PA Transit news releases, Tri-State Rivers Seminar, Testimony of the Port Authority of Allegheny County, Symposium on Transportation Issues, Pittsburgh Light Rail Transit Reconstruction, Highway Planning and Research Work Program; Presentation folder on – Federal Funding of Transit; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board minutes and agendas, Port Authority People Flyer, PA Transit news releases</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1979" type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4929f1c5e1b69a710d81491911bca57" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">57</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref80_k54" level="file"><did><unittitle>John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board and agendas, Professional correspondence, Customer Letters, Newspaper articles, PA Transit news releases, Transit Fare Summaries; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Quarterly progress report, Monthly financial reports; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, and minutes, Port Authority People Flyer, Newspaper articles, PA Transit news release</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad962c22bab7f16d41199d69f20adb40" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">59</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref81_8e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority report for fiscal year (1979-1980), South Hills Light Rail Transit, Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Spine Line Feasibility Study, Comparative Analysis Study of Alternative Transit Systems: South Hills Corridor, Executive session of the board; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda, Newspaper articles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1985" type="inclusive">1973-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_760f1f3863b93d5b8055ce257942f7c4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">60</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref82_1w0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audit (1984) – Port Authority board members, by-laws, history, financial status, and technical studies; Port Authority Equal Opportunity Program; Bound reports regarding – Second Class County Port Authority Act, Urban Transport: Sector Policy paper, Public Hearing on Proposed Service Reduction, Port Authority Proposal for new fare structure, Port Authority Strategic Plan (1987-1991), Port Authority discussion of strategic issues; Presentation folder for – Rapid Transit Conference (1989); Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Proposed Garage Rehabilitation Program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1992" type="inclusive">1971-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_53a102ad6831f18ad77030c37d4d1484" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">65</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref83_66m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Spine Line Feasibility study, Metropolitan Transportation, Riverfront Renaissance: A Comprehensive Strategy for the Pittsburgh Riverfront, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Operating &amp; Capital Improvement budget (1990); Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda and minutes, John P. Robin Port Authority resignation letter</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1993" type="inclusive">1980-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_8395bdccd859650b6fbb870190ae1ce4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">66</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref84_img" level="file"><did><unittitle>Allegheny County Transit Council – News releases, meeting agenda, and professional correspondence; Consumer Relations/Operations Committee meeting minutes, Planning and Construction meeting minutes, Administration and Finance Committee meeting minutes, documents relating to Port Authority Union and Airport Busway; Bound reports regarding – Parkway West Multi-Modal Corridor study, Port Authority Operating and Capital Improvement budgets, Phase 1 Airport Busway/Wabash HOV/Alternatives Analysis/Draft Environment Impact statement</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1984/1993" type="inclusive">1984-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ab313835d72c5281560d93ef31dd35d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">69</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref85_lf9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Administration and Finance Committee meeting minutes, Consumer Relations/Operating Committee meeting minutes, Planning and Construction Committee meeting minutes, Port Authority Operating and Capital Improvement budgets (1989-1990),; John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board and agendas, Professional correspondence, Customer letters, Newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board agenda and minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1989" type="inclusive">1988-1989</unitdate><container id="aspace_77079c2121c91cc6d2865249924d0699" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">70</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref86_14j" level="file"><did><unittitle>John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, agendas, and minutes, Port Authority of Allegheny Count Resolution, Port Authority Program for mass Transportation Services for Handicapped persons, Port Authority capital budget (1988), Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Trolley Wire-Pittsburgh Light Rail Project report, Report to the APTA Transit board members seminar, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Annual Report (1987-1987), Allegheny County Transit Council meeting minutes and agenda</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1990" type="inclusive">1982-1990</unitdate><container id="aspace_453608205c7fa43318524d828bf51a4d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">79</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref87_pu8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the Board; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority Regular meeting of the agenda and minutes, Port Authority Special meeting of the board minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">1991-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a6b871f15d287fe656a69be859dd476" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">81</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref88_za5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planning Committee of the Board of the Port Authority agenda, Testimony of the Port Authority before the House Sub-Committee on Mass Transportation; John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board and agendas, Strategic planning for transit, Absenteeism Reduction Demonstration Project, Administrative Committee of the Port Authority meeting minutes, Prototype study on management and operations for Port Authority, Professional correspondence, newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Staff report to the board, Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Minority Business Enterprise Program, Salary Administration Program; Loose documents pertaining to – Pt Regular meeting of the board agenda and minutes, Port Authority Special meeting of the board agenda, Professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1984" type="inclusive">1974-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b5bec168a87530b2dcb04ac5ef02429" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">83</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref89_vf0" level="file"><did><unittitle>John P. Robin's papers on – Port Authority Regular meetings of the board, agendas, and minutes, Professional and Inter office correspondence, Fiscal strategies for Pennsylvania, Mt. Lebanon: The Community Magazine, PA Transit News articles, Newspaper articles; Bound reports regarding – Port Authority Monthly financial reports, Port Authority Regular meeting of the board, Port Authority Quarterly progress reports; Loose documents pertaining to – Port Authority People Flyer, PA Transit news articles, Professional and Inter office correspondence, Allegheny County Planning Commission meeting minutes, Administrative Committee meeting minutes, Allegheny County Transit Council meeting minutes, Consumer Relations Committee minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1985" type="inclusive">1978-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_94434f87cf364e52e43643d26e905d01" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">86</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_gw1" level="series"><did><unittitle>Professional Publications</unittitle><unitid>VII.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1972" type="inclusive">1961-1972</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ce256770fa7b2b0d0bafa36675cfb06"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains several professional publications such as Audubon magazine, City magazine, D.A. Review magazine, Ekistics magazine, Human settlements magazine, Journal of Mammalogy, The Sun magazine, and Dialogue magazine.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref51_b5i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various bound publications including – Athens Technological Organization/Athens Center of Ekistics, Audubon magazine, Town Planning Institute Singapore Branch magazine, City magazine, D.A. Review magazine, Congo-Afrique, Ekistics magazine; Loose publications pertaining to – The American Country magazine, Architecture, Town Planning, Surveying, Engineering magazine, African Wildlife Leadership Foundation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1972" type="inclusive">1968-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_47a19c059509f9153a455197ccc137f2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref52_fw1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Exapolis 2000 &amp; Population Societies; Various bound publications including – Ekistics magazine, Human Settlements magazine, Journal of Mammology, Finance and Development magazine, Challenge Breakthrough magazine</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4e8eef7a22ba3a6c08ecc4b0ce678fe" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref53_0xy" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various bound publications including – The Sun magazine, Public Administration Newsletter, Philippine Planning Journal, Dialogue magazine, NIPA Journal, Volunteer magazine, Monthly Commentary magazine, The Sunday Times magazine</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1972" type="inclusive">1961-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_8565697065d76ebc6f8d9882ba048826" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">20</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref14_wfq" level="series"><did><unittitle>University of Pittsburgh</unittitle><unitid>VIII.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1994" type="inclusive">1985-1994</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_05eb922bcb82098b7a21cbd56226b7af"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains documents pertaining to the Advisory Council of Regional Development (ACORD), the Institute of Politics, and the PITT Benchmark Index Advisory Committee.  There are ACROD documents such as meeting minutes and agendas, expense reports, budgets, newspaper articles, and professional correspondence documents.  In addition, there are Institute of Politics documents such as meeting minutes and agendas.  The Benchmark documents include items such as meeting agendas, newspaper articles, reports, and professional correspondence documents.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref58_a6j" level="file"><did><unittitle>Advisory Council on Regional Development (ACORD) – Professional Correspondence, expense report, and budget; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional Correspondence, Institute of Politics – memorandum, Joint meeting of the board agenda and minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1993" type="inclusive">1988-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_bdeee0486dc6915255b9728e165b29cf" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">63-A</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref59_9jo" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – ACORD and Benchmarks II; Bounds reports regarding – ACORD and Pittsburgh Benchmarks; Loos documents pertaining to – Profession Correspondence, The University's Economic Development Initiatives</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1994" type="inclusive">1985-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_0aa6a3e16b06828f277c42d55ef52850" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">78</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_zxd" level="series"><did><unittitle>Urban Redevelopment Authority</unittitle><unitid>IX.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1994" type="inclusive">1943-1994</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_548ef810901b10322b9b9cb75d0d5a08"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains Urban Redevelopment Authority meeting minutes and agendas, financial statements, quarterly reports, professional correspondence documents, Executive Committee meeting minutes, Citizens Sponsoring Committee meeting minutes, Mayor Caliguiri speeches, Pittsburgh Cultural Trust District Development Committee meeting minutes and agendas, and Mayor's Task Force on Entertainment Center Development meeting minutes and agendas.  In addition, there are documents pertaining to specific projects such as the Convention Center proposal and redevelopment area plan, Lower Hill proposal, Hazelwood proposal, North Side neighborhood revitalization program, North Shore project, Market Square proposal redevelopment area plan, Smallman Street reconstruction project, Herr's Island, YMCA initiative, Buhl Science Center, Parkway East industrial park, Pittsburgh Technology Center, Washington's Landing, Forks of the Ohio National Park, and Schenely Park.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref90_euk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding - 601 Liberty, Public Sector Prospectus, Financial Study No. 5 for Public Parking Authority of Pittsburgh, Convention Center Proposal and Redevelopment Area Plan, Lower Hill Proposal and Modification No. 5 to the Plan, Hazelwood Proposal and Modification No. 1 to the Redevelopment Area Plan, Land Use and Housing Plan, City of Charleston, SC, Recommended Priority Highway System Plan, Housing Subsidy Programs, Greenway Revised Proposal and Modification No. 1 to the Redevelopment Area Plan, North Side Neighborhood Revitalization Program Progress Report, Final Technical Report, Penn/Liberty Urban Design Study, North Shore Project Report; Presentation folder; Loose documents pertaining to – Forest City Enterprises Annual Report, Charleston Waterfront Park Master Plan, Pittsburgh Perceived: A Design Image of Pittsburgh</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1983" type="inclusive">1963-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_f72d8a65f8de87a5ed27494e1a463772" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref91_ly5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding - URA Report on Examination of Financial Statements and Additional Information, URA Home Improvement Loan Program, URA Mortgage Revenue Bond Program, Analysis of Major Commercial Districts, Court Deposition, Monongahela Wharf Promenade and Parking Deck Study, Market Square Proposal Redevelopment Area Plan, Golden Triangle Association Annual Report, Downtown at CMU, ACTION-Housing, Inc. Twenty-five years of housing and neighborhood improvements, Renaissance II The Inside Story; Presentation folder containing – When Housing Rehabilitation Confronts the 80's, UDAG Luncheon Program, ATION Housing, RIDC Industrial Park; Loose documents pertaining to - Professional Correspondence, Allegheny County Marina Study, North Shore Urban Design Consulting Services, Lower Hill Redevelopment Area Plan, An Analysis of Solid Waste Disposal in Pittsburgh, Smallman Street Reconstruction Project, Homewood Commercial Revitalization Program</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1985" type="inclusive">1976-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d82016dffcf40d9c6b37fbdd53555fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref92_dqv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – Silver Lake, Report on Examination and Financial Statements, JR Associates Submission for Development of East Liberty Great High School site; Presentation folder containing – Pittsburgh Partnership for Neighborhood Development; Loose documents pertaining to – URA meeting minutes and agenda, professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1984" type="inclusive">1977-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_ddcde56dc0a2b85088d34408f64e5fa9" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref93_31n" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – North Shore Proposal for Redevelopment Activities, Homewood South Proposal and Modification No. 3 to the Redevelopment Area Plan; Loose documents pertaining o – URA meeting minutes and agenda, professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1987" type="inclusive">1977-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d34d5f3faf76173b172f12b2e141e7e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref94_r4j" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various committee meeting minutes, Bound reports regarding- Mayor's Development Workshop, Briefing Materials, Mini-Grants for Teachers, Partnerships in Education, Mount Washington: Duquesne Heights, A Program for Implementation, Mount Washington: Duquesne Heights, A Study for the Department of Parks and Rec, Solid Waste Resource Recovery: Full Scale Test Report, The Firstside Cultural District Plan: "A Strategy for Revitalization", Fox Chapel: A Comprehensive Development Plan, Community Development for Homewood-Brushton, Allegheny Conference Education Fund, Urban Redevelopment Authority: Department of Housing: Housing Subsidy Programs; Presentation folder contacting – A Landmark Proposal for Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh Hydroelectric Project Design Highlights, DiSuvero Sculpture Island Project; Loos documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Mayor's Development Council meeting minutes, Basic Expressway System: Program Status Update</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1988" type="inclusive">1977-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_42c9ad076a81c162ed04bceecf93e40e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref95_9ji" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound reports regarding – URA Quarterly report, Downtown Development in Renaissance II: Cost Benefit Study; Presentation folder containing – Garfield Jubilee Association; loose document pertaining to – URA meeting minutes and agenda, Quarterly reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1988" type="inclusive">1979-1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_91941003485a82423910ab9c831b4b8c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">32-A</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref96_tlc" level="file"><did><unittitle>United Manchester Redevelopment Authority report, URA Agenda, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding – Herr's Island Pittsburgh Proposal for Redevelopment Activity, URA Report on Examination and Financial Statements; Loose documents pertaining to – URA agenda and memorandum, Newspaper articles, City of Pittsburgh Neighborhood Revitalization Mortgage Loan Program, Modification No. 5 to the Lower Hill Area Plan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1984" type="inclusive">1970-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6883d7fa5b68f9cf1502701824dc78c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">34</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref97_2qj" level="file"><did><unittitle>URA Bloomfield/Garfield, URA Financial Department: CEO Venture Fund, URA YMCA Building, Buhl Science Center, Market Square; Presentation folder containing – Manchester Citizens Corporation; Bound reports regarding - Women Business Enterprise in Pittsburgh: Research, Policy Analysis, Program Development, Economic Development Department: 1986 Report, A generation of Economic Change in the City of Pittsburgh, Neighborhood Food Stores in Pittsburgh, Economic Development Department: 1991 Annual Report, Performance Audit of Economic Development Department, Pittsburgh's Neighborhood Business District: Revitalization Program, Urban Redevelopment Authority Quarterly Reports, Financial Assistance Programs, Urban Redevelopment Authority Financial Statements; Loose documents pertaining to – URA memorandum, professional correspondence, Manchester proposal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1994" type="inclusive">1977-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1e34477f3a7981e417e6f411cec7524" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">62</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref98_7rv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Allegheny County Planning agenda and minutes, Bridges, Professional correspondence; Bound reports regarding - Institute of Politics Reports, Issues, The University of Pittsburgh Issues Publications, Taking Flight: Pittsburgh International Airport, Airport Area Economic Development, Annual Report on Southwestern Pennsylvania's Bridge Conditions, Southwestern PA Regional Planning Commission (SPRPC) Reports, Pittsburgh Magazine, Remaking the Monongahela Valley; Loose documents pertaining to – Airport Area Development Commission, Professional correspondence Newspaper articles, Southwester PA Regional Planning Commission reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1993" type="inclusive">1976-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_833dfecc932d8f66c60bd5637822468c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">63-B</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref99_tu1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mayor Richard: Speeches, Grant Street, URA Real Estate Department, Clark Candy Company Committee, People Movers, URA Strategy 21; Bound reports regarding - Pittsburgh Technology and Industry Park: Preliminary Land Development Plan, Parkway East Industrial Park: A Proposal, Pittsburgh Technology Center: Final Land Development Plan, Market Square: First Draft, Civic Arena/Melody Tent Project, Pennsylvania Brighton: Redevelopment Proposal, Implementation Plan &amp; Financial Proposal: Three Rives Corporate Center, Proposal: Three Rives Corporate Center, The Role of Downtown People Movers in Renaissance II; Presentation folder containing – Reshaping the Technological Landscape; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, URA Memorandum, Newspaper articles, Detailed description of final Horizontal Elevator Study, Three Rivers Stadium Proposal</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1992" type="inclusive">1977-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_d76421a7959e2fe4fc33e1bbf3187b76" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">64</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref100_rzb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carley Capital Group, Pirates; Bound reports regarding - An Evaluation of the North Side Revitalization Program, Request for Proposals: North Shore Place, Riverside Presentation Summary, Crawford Roberts: Request for Proposals, Housing Subsidy Programs, Home Improvement Loan Program: Status Report, Make Yourself at Home: On Pittsburgh's North Side, An Evaluation of The Rental Housing Improvement Program, The Vacant Property Review Committee: Report; Presentation folder containing – North Side Civic Development Council, Dravo Tower; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, URA Memorandum, Newspaper articles, reports, Urban Development Law</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1993" type="inclusive">1977-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_c68872107fee87dca29f7eae5f5aa778" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">67</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref101_4vk" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – Pittsburgh Convention Center, Washington's Landing; Bound reports regarding - Pennsylvania Railroad Terminal Building Study, Convention Center: Proposal and Redevelopment Area Plan, Market Study: Proposed Convention Center Hotel, Convention Center Redevelopment Area Plan &amp; Proposal, David L. Lawrence Convention Center Expansion Study, Herr's Island Conference Center Study – Phase I, Herr's Island: Proposal for Redevelopment Activities, Redevelopment Area Plan, Allegheny County Marina Study, Washington's Landing Phase II Proposals, Washington's Land Promotional Material, Residential Analysis: Washington's Landing; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, Newspaper articles, Washington's Landing, Penn Central Station, Herr's Landing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1991" type="inclusive">1978-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e5f0e203ba7d37499652e1dbbd595c7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">68</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref102_q1c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hill District PAC, PA Economy League, Northside, Greyhound and Trailways; Bound reports regarding – Chinatown on the Allegheny, Shadyside Parking Facility Plan, Tasso Katselas Architect Planner; Presentation folders containing – Tour of URA Projects for 12th Floor, Motor Square Garden Fact Sheet, magazine articles; Loose documents pertaining to – URA memorandum, Professional correspondence, Shadyside Parking garage and Walnut Street Business District, Disposition Strategy for South Side Site</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1993" type="inclusive">1975-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c9d2a56bbb14642625df718503a4845" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">71</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref103_rb2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minority Business Initiative, Women Owned Business Enterprise Directory, URA memorandum, Profession correspondence; Bound reports regarding – A Plan for Pittsburgh's Golden Triangle, Pittsburgh Wall Street District, Cities Reborn; Various magazines; Presentation folder containing – Andy Warhol Museum; Loose documents pertaining to – Minority/Women Business Enterprise reports, magazine articles, newspaper articles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1993" type="inclusive">1962-1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_66f0d850601af76e43097bf00e61aba4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">72</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref104_a8q" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various meeting agendas and minutes; Bound reports regarding – Various redevelopment proposals; Loose documents pertaining to – URA meeting agendas</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1994" type="inclusive">1985-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e2173210eb64fe1c955af8de569c87d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">73</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref105_edq" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various board meeting agendas and minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1991" type="inclusive">1989-1991</unitdate><container id="aspace_24564ba0b869b48ce40149f0e0f19d1f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">74</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref106_zh7" level="file"><did><unittitle>URA Mayor's Development Council –Agenda, minutes, and Professional correspondence; various documents concerning – Forks of the Ohio National Park, Oakland Portal, Schenley Park, Presidential Committee on the Library, Allegheny County on Community Development, Mon0Ohio Development and Reconstruction Commission; Bound reports regarding – Forks of the Ohio national park Alternatives Study, The Plan for the Pittsburgh Riverfront, Allegheny County Marina Study, The Headwaters District, Allegheny River Edge Park; Presentation folders containing – Schenley Park Centennial; Lose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1992" type="inclusive">1943-1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f57bf325b40c3bfab7234d0325808bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">77</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref107_12w" level="file"><did><unittitle>Schenley Plaza, Pittsburgh City Planning Commission meeting agenda and minutes, various documents concerning – Oakland Taskforce, Pittsburgh Cultural District Taskforce, and the Mayor's Taskforce; Bound reports regarding - The Economic Impact and Financial Health of the Arts in Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh Downtown Cultural District, The Firstside Cultural District Plan: A Strategy for Revitalization, The Plan for the Cultural District; Presentation folder containing – Three Rivers Stadium; Loose documents pertaining to – Professional correspondence, meeting minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1994" type="inclusive">1975-1994</unitdate><container id="aspace_31032d2c194ff90bdaafc20445333ffb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">80</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref16_6dj" level="series"><did><unittitle>The World Bank</unittitle><unitid>X.</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1973" type="inclusive">1959-1973</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_375af3dcb57ff33dc5ff3a68e2e02162"><head>Scope and Content Notes</head><p>This series contains documents pertaining to numerous countries such as Calcutta, Colombia, Iran, Singapore, Thailand, Turkey, Pakistan, Brazil, East Africa, and Jamaica.  In addition there are several World Bank Annual Reports.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_ref60_i27" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Urbanization Problem in Less Developed Countries report, Urbanization: An Interim Policy Paper, Metropolitanization and National Policies for Growth, Speeches and papers by McNamara and others, Compound and Discounting Tables, Organization Chart, ; Various documents concerning – Calcutta, Columbia, Iran, Singapore, Thailand, Turkey, Morocco, Jamaica, Nigeria, Kenya; Bound reports regarding – World Bank Annual Reports, The Indonesia Economy: Development Trends and Foreign Aid Requirements, Constraints Committee, Professional Correspondence, Report on Bombay</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1973" type="inclusive">1964-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_092031d1af5342bec1bf30aaf7c5c80f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">10</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref61_88m" level="file"><did><unittitle>Course on Managing Urban Growth, Tourist maps; various documents concerning – Brazil (in Portuguese)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1973" type="inclusive">1967-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8e4bd2498f016fb3cc13d31931971b7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref62_4br" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – French-Congo, Environmental Studies School (England), Bound reports regarding – British Aid Programme, IFHP Bulletin, Overseas Development Administration, Congo, Educational Workshop: Planning and Building for Development, Several in different languages</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1971" type="inclusive">1961-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_352290112e95df0d8beffcd0c7208974" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref63_ar7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Various documents concerning – United Arab Republic, Egypt, Ethiopia, East Africa; Bound reports regarding – Ethiopia</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1970" type="inclusive">1959-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_e032822107d6d196b1b89d97c17293d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">13-A</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
