<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">us-ppiu-ais197746</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Southern Blacks' Migration to Pittsburgh Oral History Project, 1973-1977 <num>AIS.1977.46</num></titleproper><author>Frank Zabrosky. Additional description was created and included in this finding aid by Israel Herndon from September-November, 2021.</author><sponsor>Funding for the digitization and transcriptions of the oral histories was provided by the Recordings At Risk Program of the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR), in 2022-2023.</sponsor></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>ULS Archives &amp; Special Collections</publisher><p><date>February 7, 1978</date></p><address><addressline>University of Pittsburgh Library System</addressline><addressline>Archives &amp; Special Collections</addressline><addressline>Website: library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 412-648-3232 (Thomas) | 412-648-8190 (Hillman)</addressline><addressline>Contact Us: www.library.pitt.edu/ask-archivist</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.pitt.edu/archives-special-collections" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-12 12:34:32 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>ULS Archives &amp; Special Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Southern Blacks' Migration to Pittsburgh Oral History Project</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="aacr" source="local">Gottlieb, Peter</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>AIS.1977.46</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/resources/812</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">33 cassette_tapes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">(23 interviews)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1977" type="inclusive">1973-1977</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_e6e43fc61b395937de536d6c2ce195bb" label="Abstract">This oral history collection contains 23 interviews conducted by Peter Gottlieb for his Southern Blacks' Migration to Pittsburgh oral history project. It consists of 33 cassette tapes and nine interview indexes. The project documents the experience of individuals who migrated from the southern United States to the Pittsburgh area between 1916 and 1930. The content of the interviews span the life histories of the individuals from the turn of the century to 1976.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ed4ef026a2ca3d79b334682e5bfb8e63">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Interviewees are only identifiable by their first name and the initial of their surname.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_bc1c53126505c770f5d237480a1d4c47">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Gift of Peter Gottlieb in 1978.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <odd id="aspace_f4c8331cf7de48ad9f43ba17ba4ffd96">
    <head>Previous Citation</head>
<p>Recordings of the Southern Blacks' Migration to Pittsburgh Oral History Project, 1916-1930, AIS.1977.46, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cab8e381230b6a04c53bdcfaab57d5d8">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Southern Blacks' Migration to Pittsburgh Oral History Project, 1973-1977, AIS.1977.46, Archives &amp; Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_37c276882e84be67ebca624fda3758e6">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was processed by Frank Zabrosky on February 7, 1978. Additional abstracts were written by Israel Herndon in 2021.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_e164911759f1199f39b99a5f73664ab0">
    <head>Scope and Content Notes</head>
<p>For his dissertation, "Making Their Way: Southern Blacks' Migration to Pittsburgh, 1916-1930" (Ph.D., University of Pittsburgh, 1977), Peter Gottlieb interviewed 23 individuals who migrated from the south United States to Pittsburgh and vicinity, particularly Homestead, between 1916 and 1930. After incorporating the information into his dissertation, Gottlieb deposited copies of the interviews with the Archives Service Center. </p><p>The collection consists of 23 interviews on 33 cassette tapes. The content of the interviews span the life histories of the individuals and address the topics of community and family life from the turn of the century to 1976. The majority of the interviews range from 80 to 100 minutes.  Some of the tapes were transferred from reel-to-reel tapes held and retained by Mr. Gottlieb onto audio cassette tapes. </p><p>The collection also contains 12 interview indexes with subject descriptions that have been compiled by Mr. Gottlieb to accompany the selected tapes. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3409d9398ed6d9274ff5123f2bc32a59">
    <head>Copyright</head>
<p>The University of Pittsburgh holds the property rights to the material in this collection, but the copyright is still held by the original creator/author. Researchers are therefore advised to follow the regulations set forth in the U.S. Copyright Code when publishing, quoting, or reproducing material from this collection without the consent of the creator/author or that go beyond what is allowed by fair use.</p>  </userestrict>
  <altformavail id="aspace_c84ec0407d421e1d239e244fb551321c">
    <head>Availability of electronic audio recordings</head>
<p>All cassette tapes have been transferred to digital audio files are are available online:</p><p>https://historicpittsburgh.org/collection/southern-blacks-migration-pittsburgh-oral-history-project</p><p>https://digital.library.pitt.edu/collection/southern-blacks-migration-pittsburgh-oral-history-project</p>  </altformavail>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Oral histories (Document genres)</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Southern States -- Emigration and immigration</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Emigration and immigration</geogname>
    <subject source="ulstag">Ethnic groups</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- History</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Interviews</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Interviews</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ref11_22s" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Alfred B.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177430</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">April 21, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_edba64d0161ec6bfa71f32c743731c69" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_572a921dbe812b38a389dc251c816682" parent="aspace_edba64d0161ec6bfa71f32c743731c69" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_5cdeb8a2fecf5e8797ab09dede72cc03" parent="aspace_572a921dbe812b38a389dc251c816682" type="cassette">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a927633b33b7090e5125a12edd7dbae"><head>Abstract</head><p>Alfred B. discusses his father's migration from Virginia to Homestead, the work his father did in Virginia, and his father's involvement in the 1892 Homestead strike as a strikebreaker. He also mentions where his family lived in Homestead in addition to the number of children in his family, his father's education, and return migration. Alfred then talks about his childhood growing up in Homestead, including the night life, recreational activities, the police, the community center, and neighborhood schools. He recalls his memories from the Great Migration, boarding for strangers, and the 1919 Steel strike. It is noted in the interview about Black people's sentiments concerning the strike and where they worked in the Homestead Mill. Alfred speaks about his education and the wage-earning jobs he had as an adolescent, including his parents' attitudes about such jobs. He then discusses the living process at Homestead workplaces and his adult work career, again citing his father's attitude towards this choice of work. Alfred talks about his decision to stay with his parents until they died. Alfred also reflects on his marriage and children and the history of the Second Baptist Church. He mentions the social basis of Black churches in Homestead and shares his memories of Reverend Morton. Alfred then talks about the relationship between steel companies and the Second Baptist church, including the church's efforts to instruct migrants and the subsequent attitudes that the migrants gained toward religion and churches. He goes on to speak about the holiness churches in Homestead, including his own offices in Second Baptist and some of his fraternal organizational memberships. Alfred mentions his mother's work outside of the home and the children's responsibilities inside the home, even mentioning the values instilled in him by his parents. At the end of the interview, Alfred reflects on why his father wanted him to join the ministry and where his siblings went from Homestead.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref13_c3i" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Benjamin B.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177431</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">November 30, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_520a3cab45c48b44744b062499564abd" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_bae4d06013d5968c833c682d99bc0f99" parent="aspace_520a3cab45c48b44744b062499564abd" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_9514489663f18e7f8fd304b2f2714bb8" parent="aspace_bae4d06013d5968c833c682d99bc0f99" type="cassette">2-3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5976537e3284c88ec167da80259c4f05"><head>Abstract</head><p>Benjamin B. was interviewed by Peter Gottlieb for approximately 90 minutes. In the interview, Benjamin talks about his early life in Charleston, South Carolina, and the work that his relatives did, in addition to the work he completed as an adolescent. He then gives his reasons for migrating from Charleston to Pittsburgh, particularly to Homestead, and the details involving his new positions and safety hazards at the steel mill. Benjamin also discusses the relationships between his coworkers and his boss, even citing incidents of discrimination. Benjamin then speaks about the attitude towards job supervisory versus a lower position and the composition of work happening within the shipping department. He also gives a description of work "in the old days" and talks about his residences in Homestead. At one point, he mentions his mill work schedule and boarding arrangements along with some of his leisure activities. Benjamin also discusses Reverend Nelson's work in Homestead and the migrants' attitude toward Nelson. Information about Benjamin's church membership and date joined, along with a description of Black people's places in Homestead from the 1920s-1960s, is also recorded.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref15_9p1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Caleb B.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177432</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">April 9, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_32b0ff2a0c02fb7557af47d311680b60" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_811c7b532e8d0a90075be4c86eeed9f8" parent="aspace_32b0ff2a0c02fb7557af47d311680b60" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_365912c59cbd4d55902cb8b709a2ec51" parent="aspace_811c7b532e8d0a90075be4c86eeed9f8" type="cassette">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35bafdebbcb1a67a0f5358f9bc706762"><head>Abstract</head><p>Caleb opens the interview with a conversation about his upbringing in Marion, South Carolina. It was here that his father owned two farms and raised various crops and livestock. Caleb was the 10th child out of 17 children. He was responsible for plowing the farm and this contribution prevented him from attending school. Caleb claimed that God taught him how to read in a dream after he lived in Homestead for some time. He listed his reasons for wanting to go to Homestead, the transportation he took from Richmond, Viginia, and how he stayed connected with his family back in South Carolina. Caleb described the job that he had in Pittsburgh, how long he stayed at the job, and how it compared to work on a farm. He did not plan to stay in the area because he wanted to return home to work on the family farm. As he laid roots in the area, he helped his friends who arrived in the area with finances and finding jobs. The interview then shifted to recite Caleb's Homestead residences and his wife's background. Caleb mentions his involvement in Second Baptist and his desire to preach.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref17_bso" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with John B.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177433</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">March 10, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_f69186cd22e466edeffadd480dbff4e9" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_7015d81bc3cbac3eb9b2d750e551c680" parent="aspace_f69186cd22e466edeffadd480dbff4e9" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_c5fb2786d1f06258ba249aba866927c3" parent="aspace_7015d81bc3cbac3eb9b2d750e551c680" type="cassette">5-6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_67e75d05858d1d27ebf34dc5d7e5fec4"><head>Abstract</head><p>John B. was interviewed by Peter Gottlieb for approximately 98 minutes. During the interview, John discussed his parents, siblings, grandparents, and overall family life. His father was a merchant, marine sailor, and farmer. John talks about his mother's work, the other people living with his family, where his other relatives had moved to, in addition to his schooling and relationship with his parents. During his childhood, John would perform chores on the farm, such as making trips to the Wilmington market to sell produce. He then speaks about his seasonal non-farm work and an incident with his father when John was of age. He concludes the interview talking about his migration path from North Carolina, to Richmond, Virginia, and then to Homestead, Pennsylvania, citing reasons for leaving and his parents' reaction to it.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref19_cqv" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Maria B.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177434</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">June 1, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_d16a47688e5ced3ef636c906ff5289bc" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_39cb9b3c4b166d06ce3714efc11ec03c" parent="aspace_d16a47688e5ced3ef636c906ff5289bc" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_923bb0b91ac5512e1b104cd92ca87c8c" parent="aspace_39cb9b3c4b166d06ce3714efc11ec03c" type="cassette">7 (Side 2)</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2596b660edd32922682a36c706b7f07e"><head>Abstract</head><p>The beginning of the recording is missing, but Maria's interview begins with the memories of her grandmother and the stories she told about slavery, previous generations, and her freedom. Maria recalled the work her father did in the foundry and how her mother cooked and washed laundry for other families. She was the second of thirteen children growing up in this Virginia town. Maria described her education, segregated schools, jobs she had as a child and then where she worked after her schooling finished. The interview transitioned to converse about how Maria came north, how her husband migrated, and her visits back to Virginia. She offered her opinions of Braddock, how racism differed in the north versus the south, and the racial demographics of her Pittsburgh addresses. She then distinguished northern and southern whites as well as southern and northern Black people. Maria talked about the church she joined in Pittsburgh, First Baptist, why she joined and how it contrasted to other churches she had been a member of. The interview shifted to discuss what the Great Depression was like for Maria and her family and then again changes to talk about what her family thought of her after her migration.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref21_sdg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Charner C.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177435</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">February 21, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_24515d613ff1a746e2bcb3ccb8edcdfd" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_b09e232f7a0998a9ebdf8901de2572ea" parent="aspace_24515d613ff1a746e2bcb3ccb8edcdfd" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_90d144281b9b97c46ffaee5fa23c2ecc" parent="aspace_b09e232f7a0998a9ebdf8901de2572ea" type="cassette">8-9</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f22542684c27535174f9e4215526941"><head>Abstract</head><p>In the first portion of this tape, Gottlieb recounts the portions of the interview that were unrecorded which includes Charner's childhood and early years on a farm in South Carolina. When Charner speaks, he gives a description of cotton farming and what that was like on the farmland his father rented. Then he provides his reasoning for leaving the farm to work his first job away from home as a teenager at a sawmill. Later, Charner migrated to Detriot to live with an aunt and work for a few years before arriving in Homestead. He contrasts Homestead to his previous residences and why he settled there. Charner details his wife's origins, how they met, and were married. He says there was a lack of opportunity for him in South Carolina and then goes on to specify what work, race relations, and discrimination were like in the steel mills of Pittsburgh. Charner explains the discrimination against Southern Black people from Northern Black people, and the distinctions between the two groups. He then mentions his membership at Second Baptist Church, how it differed from his Methodist upbringing, his involvement in church organizations, and the contributions of Reverend Morton to the Black community. During the discussion of Second Baptist, Charner includes a later visit he made to South Carolina and how churches appeared more integrated in the South than in Pittsburgh.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref23_kfg" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Harvey C.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177436</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">December 2, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1ef7a59216483a8bffc0cf61be221a8" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_69f875e307ad91e93bdd907f7abf3f4a" parent="aspace_d1ef7a59216483a8bffc0cf61be221a8" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_8259e44ebf84b3f8551ae147d1307b47" parent="aspace_69f875e307ad91e93bdd907f7abf3f4a" type="cassette">10-11</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1fb5b94deaae0bb1a3cfd721c5f14686"><head>Abstract</head><p>Harvey C. begins the interview with his birthplace of Alabama and goes on to list the schools he attended and the teachers who taught him. He left Alabama for Chicago before he briefly enlisted in the military. After an honorable discharge in 1919, Harvey migrated to Pittsburgh and worked in the steel mills for 39 years before he retired. He narrates the history of Clark Memorial Baptist Church, the church he attended in Pittsburgh. His story returns to Alabama, and he describes his family's farm and the crops they grew. The farmland was owned by the family, and they had tenants living on it as well. Harvey describes how his formerly enslaved grandfather eventually amassed the large property. Harvey was the youngest of seven children raised on the farm and one of five children who lived to adulthood. He eventually left Alabama for Chicago because of Southern racism. His parents and some of his siblings migrated to Homestead and he decided to join them there. He accredits his ease in obtaining a job at the mill because of an ongoing strike that had begun when he arrived. Later in his career, he would take part in strikes himself, but felt disappointed by the lack of results. Harvey elaborates on the kind of work, training, pay, and changes to his job at the mill. Harvey transitions the conversation to explain the reasons why Black Southerners migrated north, why they stayed, and the difficulties with maintaining contact with their families back home. Harvey responds to a question about the relationship and distinctions between the Clark Memorial and Second Baptist churches. Then Harvey talks about how he used his vacation time, when he visited home, and how he did not feel homesick. He concludes the interview with a conversation about being widowed, later remarried, and the community organizations that he was a part of in Pittsburgh.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref25_m4p" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Lee C.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177437</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">June 9, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6bb1b8011a2afafb8d76609aacde228" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_e06e4c841ae25ec33c3ab4f9d4039afb" parent="aspace_d6bb1b8011a2afafb8d76609aacde228" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_1747b18a3c47876000af7cefedb0f9b5" parent="aspace_e06e4c841ae25ec33c3ab4f9d4039afb" type="cassette">12</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fd6a22225644c067cf782163d4ff003e"><head>Abstract</head><p>Lee C. was born in Clarkesville, Virginia where his parents had been born and raised. His father was a preacher but worked at a mill to make ends meet for Lee and his seven siblings. When Lee was three, the family moved to Richmond, Virgina where Lee would receive a few years of education. Lee describes the school and its teachers, as well as the chores he did as a child. He left school early and financially contributed to the family by carrying groceries for a white man. Lee lists all the jobs he had in Richmond before he migrated to Pittsburgh where his brother had already moved to. The brothers both worked for Edgar Thompson Mills. Lee discusses work transportation, the racial demographics of the mill, and how he felt that all workers were treated the same regardless of their race. Lee expresses what work and life were like for him during the Great Depression. Lee then adds information about his brother's boarding house and how his wife traveled to Pittsburgh. On the side two of the tape, Lee talks about his membership at Willow Lake church and how the congregants were from various regions. The interview ends with Lee's involvement with the Mason Society.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref27_7ia" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Julia D. (pseudonym)</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177438</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">May 3, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_1dbb5f25eb582ff9f4539be386efa332" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_c88c7fce32aefaec9ac05c5724e8ee20" parent="aspace_1dbb5f25eb582ff9f4539be386efa332" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_e55c9edadaac94dac26d553496bf8d4f" parent="aspace_c88c7fce32aefaec9ac05c5724e8ee20" type="cassette">13</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae8d26fe8176e66c20c2bd62d3fcb387"><head>Abstract</head><p>Julia D. recalls her family background In Virginia where her mother and father raised their family on a farm. Her parents had thirteen children, five of which passed away, and she was one of the eight surviving children. She describes the kinds of crops they grew, the farmland, chores she and her siblings had, her childhood, and education. Julia left Virginia to work as a cook for a white family in North Carolina before arriving in Homestead in 1943. She lists her reasons for leaving North Carolina, her expectations of the North, her motives for staying in Homestead, and the other jobs she worked subsequently. In her interview, she contrasts country and city living, and says that she found no differences between Northern and Southern Black people. Julia then elaborates on what drew her to Second Baptist Church and how she became deeply involved in it. The interview is concluded with Julia mentioning the various streets she lived on in the Pittsburgh area.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref29_y93" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Jonnie F.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177439</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">April 23, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c1f362d7f081cb981c2eab7d830152f" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_ffacd23ec37a7b1d4455228f0bb3bed4" parent="aspace_5c1f362d7f081cb981c2eab7d830152f" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_42811ecfabe1589cdc87274ee01ade0c" parent="aspace_ffacd23ec37a7b1d4455228f0bb3bed4" type="cassette">14</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f23445b30948fe4dbcc9f9de26b59f7c"><head>Abstract</head><p>Jonnie F. was born in Montgomery, Alabama on a family farm that was rented by her father. She spends a few minutes delving into the dedication and care that her father had for their family and how hard he worked to provide for her and her seven siblings, especially after the passing of her mother. Jonnie described her family's education, her own learning, and a broader look at the schooling system in Alabama. During her childhood, she did many chores, and these tasks were not as gendered as other households. She was later married and moved to Birmingham, Alabama before arriving in Homestead with her husband. Jonnie detailed the types of jobs her husband had as well as the kinds of work other men in her family had. She added that she also worked and provides reasons why she had to contribute financially despite her husband's disapproval. She visited home but felt that it had changed little since her migration. She notes her family's perception that her life had changed because of her migration north. Jonnie then speaks on her relationship with religion.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref31_aq0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Joseph G.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177440</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">November 26, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_c162c89b9e80111333d2da90a031df30" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_4f7881eee9dbbddace097de437a6fcb0" parent="aspace_c162c89b9e80111333d2da90a031df30" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_8cf9f2408f432ca6eb850dfb5a0484f8" parent="aspace_4f7881eee9dbbddace097de437a6fcb0" type="cassette">15-16</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21b2d4189d0b213b910520edb1fc2c00"><head>Abstract</head><p>Joseph G. was interviewed by Peter Gottlieb for approximately 96 minutes. In the interview, Joseph reflects on his birthplace and date, parents' occupations, his education, his leaving for the North, and the other jobs he had at home and in the South. He mentions his relationship with his parents, particularly in terms of finances, and the series of moves made after leaving the South. His first mill job and the overall impression about Homestead is also noted along with his other jobs and residences. Specifically, he discusses the jobs available in the Homestead Mill after 1940, the composition of the labor gang, the leisure activities he enjoyed, and his fraternal organization. Joseph also mentions his return to the church, streetcar transportation, and the impression that Southern-born Blacks were better than Northern-born Blacks. He concluded the interview with a discussion about his wife's origins, Homestead and the welfare-community-recreational center.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref33_ra0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Walter H.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177441</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">October 25, 30, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_0716f5b4dcf1c8f7eec71370a91026f0" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_e4472046965339e9b333cb6f5c6667ca" parent="aspace_0716f5b4dcf1c8f7eec71370a91026f0" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_7a62c5089dab8b6c057decce314e0dcc" parent="aspace_e4472046965339e9b333cb6f5c6667ca" type="cassette">17-18</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5ac11d0897126a9ae3c3adafbb2fc0ac"><head>Abstract</head><p>Walter H. was interviewed by Peter Gottlieb for approximately 78 minutes. Walter reflects upon his life as a child living in Richmond, Virginia, and then migrating to Coatesville, PA. While in this area, Walter later moved to and became employed in a shipyard in Philadelphia, and he talks about taking other subsequent jobs outside of Philadelphia and his eventual return to Philadelphia. Walter then explains the origins of most migrants in Pittsburgh and how he returned to Virginia and worked on his family farm from 1921 to until his brother took over in 1923. From that point, he moved back north to Homestead and gives the reasons why he chose Pittsburgh over Philadelphia. He then mentions his first boarding house in Homestead along with details of his residences in Homestead. During the early years, Walter would make return trips to Virginia. In 1923, Walter had his first job in the mill at an open-hearth mixing house and his second job working on an O.H. furnace. He ended up moving to Cleveland, Erie, Buffalo, and then back to Homestead five months later, working in a chipper instruction mill upon his return. He cited his pay methods in the mill and having to claim unpaid wages at one point. Points of discussion in the interview included: his residence in Homestead after the Buffalo trip, his Masons initiation in 1926, mention of his activities, including the Homestead Grays, and race relations within the community and steel mill. He gave his comparisons of his earnings from working in the chipping mill versus open hearth along with his different residences in Homestead and Pittsburgh. He also gave general impressions of the living conditions in Homestead including life inside the mill for Blacks, citing where they could and could not work. Walter also mentioned how he never experienced homesickness and would travel to Virginia each year. He concludes his interview talking about Reverend Nelson's work, citing how he did not arrange board and bedding for transportation migrants.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref35_cn4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Matthew J.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177442</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">May 28, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_80825632e2a8513c2d1eebdbddea0d23" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_03442201a1d1cd923340721e72d9bb7a" parent="aspace_80825632e2a8513c2d1eebdbddea0d23" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_a5c429bb9ece0c6eba48c5a4d10dc295" parent="aspace_03442201a1d1cd923340721e72d9bb7a" type="cassette">19</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9766d62c76695065cec2490756435e17"><head>Abstract</head><p>Matthew J.'s interview begins by discussing his upbringing in South Carolina. He provides a detailed account of what education was like for southern Black children and the impact that segregation had on their learning experience. He claims the lack of freedom and the inability to fight against injustice without severe repercussions were the primary motive for Black migration from the south. Matthew then talks about his visits back home, work in the mills, and how he got hired at certain jobs. He briefly speaks about what his work life was like during the Great Depression. He backtracks and recalls the places he lived before Homestead and the types of work he did during that time. He talks about how it was common for young men from farming families to find other work during the winter months, which initially begins his gradual migration north as he followed the highest paying job. Matthew describes his wife's origins, how they were married, and why he chose to marry a southern woman over a northern one. Matthew defines "drag day" and how it impacted mill workers. The interview concludes with a conversation on how fraternal organizations changed over time.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref37_eg0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Gilbert M.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177443</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">April 9, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_627ccf8bc26d4803ec98bd204310f46a" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_303271bbc21006ad3e31567280e52ed7" parent="aspace_627ccf8bc26d4803ec98bd204310f46a" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_effc5794b048a5dfda59ba0b1b0bf05a" parent="aspace_303271bbc21006ad3e31567280e52ed7" type="cassette">20</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8a22e21e6ec83da9bfbb94d3ec68df4a"><head>Abstract</head><p>Gilbert's introduction included his birthplace in South Carolina and the work his father did as a farmer, mill and railroad worker. He was the only surviving child of his mother and father after his mother's premature death, until his father remarried and had three more children. Gilbert ran away from home at twelve years old and he listed the places he lived and the work he did until he returned home at 17 years old. He reflected on his relationship with his father and offered more details on the jobs that his dad worked. Gilbert recalled why he returned home after running away and why he left for the north once more. When he first arrived in Homestead, he did not plan to stay long but his values of family motivated him to stay. In the next portion of the interview, Gilbert talked about his three marriages and the premature passing of his first two wives. He provided differences between northern and southern women as well as marriage advice. Gilbert also mentioned his opinions of Homestead, how Homestead compared to other northern cities, how he supported his family during the Depression, and how he made connections in Pittsburgh.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref39_ox4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Joseph M.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177444</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">November 16, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_67d42378c9a332b5ef98416252c30340" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_00fb470c3170c9e8e6873dbfc3c440c7" parent="aspace_67d42378c9a332b5ef98416252c30340" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_5b77dd591f6210d868278e6826d1597d" parent="aspace_00fb470c3170c9e8e6873dbfc3c440c7" type="cassette">21-24</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_108438e51a0a804ed43ab358c45ae295"><head>Abstract</head><p>Joseph M. was interviewed by Peter Gottlieb for approximately 104 minutes. Joseph discusses his estimated date of birth and early memories, including how he lived with a doctor and helped his mother financially as part of his earliest work experience. Joseph talks about the seasonal migration in 1911 to New York and then his own migration to Pittsburgh, discussing his numerous mill jobs in Homestead. Joseph speaks of the 1921 Depression and how he took a job outside of the mill, later doing this again in the 1930's. He recalls his reason for migrating to northern places, his first time arriving in Pittsburgh, the length of time it took to get employed once there, the boarding house in Homestead on 12th Avenue, and the pool room "scene" for Black men in Pittsburgh . Joseph also reflects upon his marriage and new residence with his wife in Homestead. He converses about the activities he participated in, including joining the church, and about the different Black churches and organizational affiliations in Homestead. Joseph talks about the origin areas of migrants to Homestead and the Black leaders in the town. Discussions about the steel companies' welfare recreation centers also occurred, covering topics that included the center's creation, educational services, welfare function, and activities. Joseph then recalls the reason why Homestead selected Reverend Nelson and his activities on behalf of the Homestead Mill, including the transportation system and how the migrants felt about Nelson. He also talks about his time within the mill, discussing the ratio of transportation people that stayed to those who left, the old-time system, the supervisors' satisfaction with Black migrants, why migrants got the "hot and dirty" jobs, and the differences between the 1916-1918 migrants and northern Blacks. He concludes his interview by talking about the violence in Homestead, where the mill was in relation to the town pre-1936 and where Black mill workers lived, and the 1919 Homestead Strike.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref41_145" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Sadie M. #1</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177445</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">April 9, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a11c0be7e659f4940cf35ee8a3c3543" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_986912ccbc56dd50a3b8fa31ae8a888e" parent="aspace_7a11c0be7e659f4940cf35ee8a3c3543" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_d2ba8f892cc30e63a90a8c92b6fa7c2a" parent="aspace_986912ccbc56dd50a3b8fa31ae8a888e" type="cassette">25</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_403f2d7ae017e1eca1643836bb1bbba0"><head>Abstract</head><p>In her interview, Sadie M. talks about her family's history in Homestead and how it was a chain migration; her grandmother kept boarders in Homestead. Sadie also gives information about the beginnings of the Second Baptist church and Reverend Morton's background, including his geographic origins, self-taught education, the decision for him to quit his mill job when called to preach at Second Baptist Church in Homestead, and his salary as reverend. Additionally, Sadie reflects upon the contributions to the reverend's living expenses, how the church owned Morton's home, and reasons why Second Baptist started. She also discusses the social distinction between members of Second Baptist and Clark Memorial, going on to say that some believed that Homestead was not big enough for two Baptist churches. She talks about relationships between Second Baptist and Morton, saying that Morton tried to get unwed couples married. The discussion turned to revivals at Second Baptist and the difference between the church activities of the day and when Morton pastored the church. She also gives the geographic origins of Second Baptist's members and talks about the "states' rally" fundraising at the church. Sadie claims that most of the members of Clark Memorial hailed from Virginia, while only the older members of Second Baptist were from the South. Sadie also discusses her mother's geographic origins. Sadie then talks about the work of the missionary circle and how Second Baptist had no aid program for southern migrants. Additionally, she talks about the transportation and work of Charles Reynolds and how Second Baptist did not draw members away from Clark Memorial.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref43_mwu" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Sadie M. #2</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177446</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">May 19, 25, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_542c4369c1622f873faa790e003b8d17" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_bbb1a4c2d2fcfb8d8d825722cb830434" parent="aspace_542c4369c1622f873faa790e003b8d17" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_91e99a5829c477e6bd0a1d1d45bf9929" parent="aspace_bbb1a4c2d2fcfb8d8d825722cb830434" type="cassette">26</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab87fd38beb9a6dedf2eb5923db1207b"><head>Abstract</head><p>Sadie M. begins the interview by recounting her grandparents' birthplaces and livelihoods. She retells her early childhood memories and details her parents' upbringing. When Sadie was a young girl, her family migrated to Pittsburgh. She describes their transportation, why they chose the Pittsburgh area, and their return visits back to the south. The interview then transitions to a description of the jobs her parents held before and after migration as well as how her father's early passing impacted the family. Sadie describes the Black community in Pittsburgh and how discrimination has changed as she has gotten older. The conversation then moves to her parents' involvement in Union Baptist Church and the organizations they participated in. Sadie mentions the traditions that came from her mother that are being lost to younger generations as well as the beliefs, superstitions, and medical remedies that she inherited from her mother. In particular, Sadie focuses on the connection between dreams and prophecy and New Orleans religious influences on her mother.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref45_s8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Wesley M.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177447</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">April 2, 5, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_50d9a120bda7c56d8e01e9239c0485dc" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_2668bdba54331642ca0e5f1c8a584415" parent="aspace_50d9a120bda7c56d8e01e9239c0485dc" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_f18224892e5e6842a6d27876bfbbb203" parent="aspace_2668bdba54331642ca0e5f1c8a584415" type="cassette">27</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e661feeb8a716386ef7ac8dd9c45df80"><head>Abstract</head><p>Wesley M. was born on a farm in St. Stephens South Carolina. He was the fourth out of 13 children. Wesley describes the crops his family grew, his father's job on the railroad that covered the finances of the farm, and his brief experiences with education. When he first left the farm, he worked in a sawmill, and he articulates his reasons for leaving the farm. Then he worked in Richmond, before he migrated to Homestead where he lived in a boarding house. He explains his initial reactions to Homestead and how he got a job in the mill. He lists the roles that he had while working in the mill. Wesley details his wife's background, how they met, and how she migrated north. He then returns to discussing his job and he mentions the discrimination that Black people faced on the job. He recalls the distinctions he noticed between Northern and Southern Black people and how his migration caused his family to treat him differently. Towards the end of the interview, Wesley speaks on his experience at Second Baptist Church, how it differed from the church he grew up in, and what the membership of the church was like. During the final portion of the interview, Wesley asserts that he still views himself as a Southerner regardless of how long he has lived in the North.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref46_q7u" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Lillyan P.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177448</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">November 9, 10, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f47a2b7190b4a91a9d1e2d96847f9da" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_8f93bca9cccd3e9133f61c78892b5200" parent="aspace_0f47a2b7190b4a91a9d1e2d96847f9da" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_5870150536964d6ccbcd5e9da459f097" parent="aspace_8f93bca9cccd3e9133f61c78892b5200" type="cassette">28</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a172449572f890ba49f4fbb971f53613"><head>Abstract</head><p>Lillyan P. was interviewed by Peter Gottlieb for approximately 64 minutes. During the interview, Lillyan talked about her birthplace and family, education, profession as a teacher, and marriage/information about her husband. She then talks about her husband's migration from North Carolina to Virginia and his occupations at the time of their first meeting and after their marriage. When it came time to migrate to Homestead, Lillyan's husband went first and sent for her later in 1925. Lillyan then talks about her first reactions to living in Homestead, including the housing, her husband's arrangements for her arrival, memories of her Slavic neighbors, and her daily activities inside the house. Lillyan gives a description of a Black person's position in Homestead as well. She also provides information about the organizations and affiliations that she and her husband were a part of, both inside and outside of the church. Additionally, she gives information about the storefront churches in Homestead, boarders with Powells at Dixon St., and the jobs her husband had in the mill. She goes on to list her other residences, the year they purchased their first used car, and other clubs she was associated with, like the formation of the Husband and Wives club. She provides information about the leader of the Homestead Black community and her emotional commitment to the home in Virginia up until 1949. To conclude the interview, Lillyan talks about other "Petersburg-ers" in Homestead and about Grover Nelson, who was a Homestead Mill welfare worker.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref49_txa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Ed R.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177449</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">June 10, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_519e6e78e55aabb8ed1e124783bbca6b" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_078be090141c6ecc19388bd49f2b5b37" parent="aspace_519e6e78e55aabb8ed1e124783bbca6b" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_acfa62ed23b0d4f4fa1c5483342d0da9" parent="aspace_078be090141c6ecc19388bd49f2b5b37" type="cassette">29 (Side 2), 30</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c0030cebe6b867fb4a63b0a61f4d60fb"><head>Abstract</head><p>Ed's interview opens with an illustration of peanut farming and the salary he made working on a farm as a child. His parents moved to Richmond, Virginia while he stayed in the country with his grandparents. He eventually joined his parents to further his education, despite his distaste for the city. Ed continues to describe his education and the jobs his parents and grandparents held. Eventually his mother moved to Pittsburgh, and he joined her. Then Ed lists off the various jobs that he worked, why he quit, and his career in the police force. Ed briefly tells the story of how he and his wife met, married, and raised their children. He also distinguishes northern and southern Black people. Then he recalls his previous addresses as well as their racial and ethnic demographics. Ed discusses why he joined New Hope Baptist Church. The interview concludes with what motivated Ed to continue his education as an adult.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref51_0u3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Victoria S.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177450</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">May 25, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ea190811a0c8b2c6e53a82670cfbe0f" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_0491d8ed592773d6b75823f9b3cb7950" parent="aspace_7ea190811a0c8b2c6e53a82670cfbe0f" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_5a6fee2e39d4af80896c277e81680bb1" parent="aspace_0491d8ed592773d6b75823f9b3cb7950" type="cassette">29 (Side 1)</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_132b9b585750a62b70217b569174fbaa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Victoria S. discusses her roots in Louisiana and her father's German ancestry. She is the youngest of 13 siblings, though only one other survived to adulthood. Her father was an engineer in Port Arthur, Texas and her mother was a housekeeper. Victoria S. details her experiences with segregation and leaving school at an early age to take care of her family after her father's passing. She came to Pittsburgh with her husband in 1942 to have better opportunities for her children. Victoria S.'s husband was employed by Westinghouse. She was a member of the Triedstone Baptist Church and an active member of Eastern Star.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref53_auf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with John T.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177451</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">November 1, 23, 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_db96f19d23dfcb2ef5eb681cee28ca60" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_c812cdd7132ddbe05b42910eb8c172d0" parent="aspace_db96f19d23dfcb2ef5eb681cee28ca60" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_c5e308f9e511699e5ed97a7343be5bec" parent="aspace_c812cdd7132ddbe05b42910eb8c172d0" type="cassette">31-33</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_80354d66c4838d89f38d216b818f8750"><head>Abstract</head><p>John T. reflects on his early life, including his birth date and place, his childhood home and chores, his parents' work, and his education in Virginia, including his theological studies. John discusses his marriage, tailoring, pressing, and barbershop times in his life. He notes his migration to Pittsburgh and the reasons for leaving North Carolina and migrating to Columbus, Ohio, and then to Rankin, PA, saying that the "mills [were] shutting down, no steel". He speaks about his jobs at the Westinghouse Steel Mill, including discussions about his pay (?), where Black people worked within Westinghouse in 1920, racial discrimination in the South, and about his first residence in Braddock. He then reflects on his wife's home and date of their marriage, going on to speak about welfare workers at the Edgar Thompson Mill. John also discusses the democratic political organization in Braddock among Black people and how to get good jobs. Additionally, John mentions a period of time, 1906-1911, where he worked on a dairy farm in New Jersey and explains how he obtained the position. He then gave his impression of Braddock, the length of time between his arrival in Braddock and his wife's arrival, his second residence there, and the Black migrants and churches within the town. The comparison between Northern-born versus Southern-born Blacks also came up in conversation before he talked about his career in the church. He talks about the contributions made to the church by Westinghouse executives and remarks that he "always wanted to be independent" in relation to the congregation as his position of a pastor within the church. He concludes the interview by talking about how he helped Black people get jobs and his general services to the community.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_ref55_owb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interview with Lee T.</unittitle><unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/10/archival_objects/177452</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">May 26, 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e7a29f9d6dded4fcc7b756a0c549004" label="Audio" type="audio-cabinet">1</container><container id="aspace_7b521d85b3d06c590b75487f6de241ff" parent="aspace_1e7a29f9d6dded4fcc7b756a0c549004" type="drawer">7</container><container id="aspace_5cb717cbd0ef694676d231fd204d81be" parent="aspace_7b521d85b3d06c590b75487f6de241ff" type="cassette">7 (Side 1)</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db9d75ce1fc9543fe7cb53b3bc28f15d"><head>Abstract</head><p>During this interview with Lee T. there was also a third person present who Lee referred to in order to confirm the more specific details of his life. He was born in South Carolina and was raised on a farm. Lee described the kinds of crops that were grown, what sharecropping meant, how he and his siblings contributed to farm work, and the behavioral expectations for children at the time. Lee never attended school but mentions his Sunday school. He argues that formal education cannot teach morality in the same way that church programs can. He worked on his own farm in South Carolina before he migrated north. After his wife's premature passing, Lee's three children remained in the south as he provided for them. In Homestead, he joined the Second Baptist Church, and he lists the other churches he attended in the area. Lee recalls work during the Great Depression and fraternal organizations.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
